（迈阿密）
外面冷死人了
It's fucking cold outside.
收音机说会降到华氏34度
That guy on the radio said it's going down to 34.
34度
It's 34.
妈的，都快结冰了
That's freezing, for chrissakes.
阿智，你在发什么呆？
Yo, Chili. What? You spacing?
葛蓝威要关了
They're closing down the Granville.
你知道碧斯坎街那家戏院吧？
You know, that theater down on Biscayne?
老板欠老莫几千块
That guy owes Momo a couple G's.
知道，我认为老莫 应该把它买下来
I know. I was thinking maybe Momo should buy it.
我可以帮他经营 放贾格纳的老电影
I could run it. Show old Cagney movies.
老莫买一家破电影院 专放没人看的电影干嘛？
Why would Momo want a theater that shows movies no one wants to see?
除非把它改成某种色情场所 但他对这种事没兴趣
Outside of making it a porno house, he's not going to give a fuck.
我来跟阿智谈
I'm gonna go talk to this Chili.
- 你有别的工作 - 好啦…好啦
- Besides, you got a job. - Yeah. Yeah.
雷！你好吗？
How you doing, Ray?
很好，你呢？
Good. You?
这是什么鸟天气？
Okay. Can you believe this weather?
迈阿密海滩耶
Miami Beach, for chrissakes!
智利帕玛
Chili Palmer.
外面冷飕飕 阿智躲起来打哆嗦
It's chilly outside, and it's Chili inside.
阿智就是这个死样子！
It's a regular fucking chilifest.
你好吗，雷？
How you doing?
显然比你好多了
Obviously much better than you, Chili.
- 说得好 - 是啊
That was a good one.
等你发完呆
When you're done staring out the window...
到办公室来找我
I'll meet you back at the office.
- 嘿！我的外套呢？ - 不在里面吗？
- Where's my coat? - It's not one of these?
黑皮夹克，长度到指尖
Do you see a black leather jacket...
（我们不会为失物负责）
像帕西诺在 “绝命卧底”里穿的那一件？
like Pacino wore in 'Serpico'?
如果没有，你得赔我379元
- 'Cause if you don't, you owe me $379.
- 你可能没看到警告牌 - 看到了
- See the sign?
我不是来阳光佛罗里达 挨寒受冻的，懂我的意思吗？
I didn't come to Florida to freeze my ass off.
找到我的外套，或赔我379元 我前妻帮我在亚历山大买的
Find my coat or give me the $379 my ex-wife paid for it.
等等，雷朋斯偷走我的外套？
Wait a minute. Ray Bones took my coat?
他不是偷 借用一下
No, he didn't take it. He borrowed it.
因为别人拿了他的外套
'Cause someone took his coat.
所以巴波尼先生试穿另一件 还蛮合身的
So Mr.Barboni tried this other coat. It fit him good.
那是我的外套
That was my coat.
他只是穿回家，不会要你的啦
He was wearing it home. He's not gonna keep it.
我的汽车钥匙在那件外套里
My car keys are in that coat.
巴波尼先生是我的好顾客 他是吉米凯普的手下
Mr.Barboni is a good customer. He works for Jimmy Capp.
我知道他是谁的手下 你的电话在哪里？
I know who he works for. Where's your phone?
这边
This way.
你确定是雷朋斯拿走外套的？
Are you sure it was Ray Bones that took the coat?
那个人是这么说的
That's what the man said.
电视气象报告说 明天是温暖的好天气
Tomorrow, I see on the TV weather, is going to be nice and warm.
- 不需要穿外套的 - 就是这里
- You don't need the coat. - This is it.
拿回外套就好 不要惹是生非好吗？
Hey, Chili. Get the coat. Just don't piss the guy off, okay?
不然我们得打电话给老莫 向他报告整个经过情形
Then we're gonna have to call Momo and straighten the whole thing out.
浪费他的时间，老莫会不爽的 没有必要
And Momo'll be pissed off for wasting his time. We don't need that, eh?
别担心，我不会多说废话的
Don't worry. I'm not saying any more than I have to, if that.
好，好，好，等一下
Yeah, yeah. Just a minute.
干嘛，你疯啦？
What! Are you fucking nuts?
我的鼻子！
My nose! My nose!
（里奇理发店）
（营业中）
（休息中）
哇靠！
Holy shit!
赶快报警！
Somebody call 9-fucking-1-1!
你要我怎么办 为一件外套宣战不成？
What do you want me to do? Go to war over a fucking coat?
他没杀你算你走运
You're lucky the guy didn't kill you.
那件外套是他的圣诞礼物
The coat was a Christmas present, for chrissakes.
听我说，吉米
Listen to me, Jimmy.
你要管管这家伙 他像疯狗一样到处乱咬
You gotta do something about this guy. He's running amok.
他对我们一点敬意都没有
He's got no fucking respect for none of us.
他是对你没有敬意
He's got no respect for you.
我不管这种鸟事！ 智利帕玛不是我的人
I don't got to do shit. Chili Palmer don't work for me.
他是布鲁克林老莫的人
He works for Momo up in Brooklyn.
只要有老莫在的一天 智利帕玛就能高枕无忧
As long as Momo's around, nothing happens to Chili.
你懂吗？
Do you understand?
这边
Over here.
（布鲁克林）
到了，老莫
We're here, Momo.
这地方你们都查清楚了吧 我一个人进去
I hope you checked this place out good, 'cause I'm going in there alone...
我可不想出什么意外
and I don't want no fucking surprises.
查过了，没问题的，老莫
I checked everything, Momo.
哪一位？
Who is it?
老莫
It's Momo.
进来
Get in here.
（老莫65岁生日快乐）
大惊喜！
Surprise!
《黑道当家》
你这话什么意思- -  你再也没办法睡觉？
So you're trying to say you're never going to sleep again?
不，我说的是没办法上床 两者是不一样的
No, I said I'm never going to bed. There's a difference.
这篇文章说大多数人死在床上
This article says that most people die in their beds.
我觉得只要不上床 应该就很安全
As long as I stay out of bed, I'm safe.
什么？这是我听过最蠢的话 那你要睡哪里？
What? That's the dumbest thing I ever heard of. Where you gonna sleep?
躺椅 我的电视间有张褐色躺椅
In my recliner. You know, the tan one in the TV room?
或者去咖啡店 把帽子压低，睡在椅子上
Or I'll go to a coffee shop, slide into a booth, pull my hat down.
你听过有几个人死在咖啡厅？
How many people you know died in a coffee shop?
这是正常理发店 还是同志理发店？
You cut straight hair in here or just fags?
朋斯，你头上的疤好大一块
Hey, Bones. That's quite a scar you got on your head.
怎么不叫他们剪一块地毯？ 帮你贴上去遮起来？
Why don't you have these guys fit you with a rug, cover it up for you?
你们两个老头到公园去下棋
You two geezers take your game to the park.
他就是老大 听不懂我的话吗，笨蛋？
This man is the man. You understand what I'm saying, motherfucker?
他叫朋斯先生 以后要称呼他朋斯先生
He's Mr.Bones, and you speak to Mr.Bones from now on.
拜托，你可以找一个 比较称头的老板吧？
You can do better than him, can't you?
这年头不好找哦 除非你会说西班牙话
Not these days. Not unless you speak Spanish.
你有个人欠债不还 里欧迪佛的钱拖了6周了
You got a miss. Leo Devoe. He's six weeks over.
他死了
He's dead.
你怎么知道他死了？ 他告诉你的？
How do you know? Did he tell you?
对，他跟我说他死了
Yeah, he told me that he was dead.
亲口说的？
Personally?
是的，雷，他亲口跟我说他死于
Yeah, he personally told me he got killed...
上个月发生的坠机事件中
in that getaway jet crash that happened a month ago.
说不定他保了飞行安全险 去问问他太太
Maybe he took out flight insurance. Check with his wife.
你自己去问，现在那是你的事
You check it out. It's your book now.
他在联邦公路有几家干洗店
He owns some dry cleaning store over on Federal Highway.
让我来跟你解释一件事 老莫已经死了
Let me explain something to you. Momo is dead.
那表示他所有的一切 现在都归吉米凯普管，包括你
Which means everything he had now belongs to Jimmy Capp, including you.
也就是说，我现在所说的 就代表吉米的意思
Which also means that when I speak, I speak for Jimmy.
比如，从现在起 你他妈给我放尊重一点
E.g., from now on, you start showing me the proper fucking respect.
“比如”的意思是“举例” 我想你应该说“亦即”
E.g. means 'for example.' I think you want to say 'i.e.'
- 放屁，那是“因此”的意思 - 不信你问他
- Bullshit. It's short for 'ergo.' - Ask your man.
据我所知 “比如”的意思是“举例”
To the best of my knowledge, e.g. means 'for example.'
管他“比如”“亦即”
E.g., i.e., fuck you!
我的重点是去你妈的 我说“跳”
The point is: When I say, 'Jump...'
你就说“好的” 懂吗？
you say, 'Okay!' Okay?
是的，雷，好的
- Yeah. Okay. - All right.
你现在欠我干洗店的1万5
You owe me the dry cleaner's 15 G's plus the juice...
外加利息…
which is another...
2千7
2,700.
你可以跟他老婆要，或自掏腰包 我管不着
Get it from his wife or out of your own pocket. I don't give a fuck.
但我不想看到有人拖欠债款
But you never hand me a book with a miss.
回头见，雷
We'll see you, Ray.
去找干洗店老板娘 给你三天时间
Go see the dry cleaner's wife. You got three days.
那次我跟你说不要惹毛他 你记得…
I told you not to piss him off.
不要再说了，好吗？
Don't say another fucking word. All right?
我讨厌开干洗店
I hate the dry cleaning business.
整天关在家里面对机器
I hate being inside all day around all those machines.
一定很热吧
Must be hot.
你根本不知道有多热
You have no idea how hot it is.
费，我…我在想…
You know, Fay, I was wondering...
里欧是否有人寿保险？
did Leo have life insurance?
据我所知是没有
I don't know of any.
我信任你，阿智
I trust you, Chili.
虽然你是流氓 但你是个正直的人
I think you're a decent type of man. Even if you are a crook.
谢谢你，费
Thank you. Thank you, Fay.
我希望他真的死了
I wish he really was dead.
他是个混蛋
He's a son of a bitch.
（马蹄铁 埃尔波特尔）
（拉斯维加斯）
对，就是他 他自称叫赖瑞丹密尔
That's him, all right. Called himself 'Larry De Mille.'
每个女艺人他都想染指
Hit on every showgirl in town.
他跟我说他是迈阿密干洗大王 白痴一个
Tell them he was the 'Martinizing King' of Miami. What a moron!
你想找他，他在洛杉矶
He's in LA.
摸鸡尾酒女郎屁股事件后 我们把他送走了
Put him on a plane. He spanked one of my cocktail girls.
里欧摸鸡尾酒女郎屁股？
Leo spanked her?
事情是这样的…
Apparently...
他邀她到圣塔阿尼塔赌赛马
he invites her to the track to play the ponies with him.
她严词拒绝了他 他却拍了她臀部一掌
She tells him what he can do with that. He gives her one on the tush.
我猜她应该是一个人去赌马了
My guess, he's by his lonesome at the track right now.
阿智，如果你要去洛杉矶 这家伙欠我们15万
If you go to LA, this guy owes us 150 grand.
拖60天了 他是个电影制片
Sixty days over. Some movie producer.
- 电影制片？真的？ - 是的
Movie producer? Really?
- 我可以帮这个忙 - 感谢
- Why not? - Appreciate that, man.
你会喜欢这家伙的 又是白痴一个
You're gonna love this guy. Another fucking moron.
哈利辛
Harry Zimm.
（洛杉矶）
好啦，多谢
Thanks a bunch.
（欢迎光临洛杉矶）
- 车在哪？ - 就在那边
- Where is it? - It's right there.
- 什么车？ - 奥斯摩比侧影
- What is that? - It's an Oldsmobile Silhouette.
我订的是凯迪拉克
I ordered a Cadillac.
它是凯迪拉克级的迷你厢型车
That's the Cadillac of minivans.
开什么玩笑？
Are you kidding me?
你要找的拉提杰拉租车在那边
If you want, La Tijera Car Rental is right over there...
我想他们只有福斯的敞篷车
but I think all they got is Rabbit convertibles.
还是这辆凯迪拉克 迷你厢型车好了
I guess I'll take the Cadillac of minivans.
哈利！
Harry.
起来！楼下有人
Goddamn it, wake up. Somebody's downstairs.
怎么啦？
What's wrong?
楼下有人
Somebody's downstairs.
安静，你听！
Be quiet. Listen.
没听到声音啊
I don't hear anything.
有啦
Right there.
电视声
That's the television.
我先上楼，你在楼下喝酒
When I came upstairs, you stayed downstairs to finish your drink.
我叫你喝完时把电视关掉的
I told you to turn off the television when you were through.
我也跟你说你可以睡佣人房
I also told you you could sleep in the maid's room.
有啊，我关啦 我用遥控器关的
I did that. I turned the television off with the remote thing...
然后把遥控器放地上
then I laid it on the floor.
知道可能发生什么事吗？
You know what could've happened?
狗进来踩到遥控器 又把电视打开了
The dog came in, stepped on it and turned the TV back on.
我没养狗
I don't have a dog, Harry.
没有？
You don't?
墨菲哪去了？
What happened to Muffy?
你要下楼去还是要我去？
Are you going down there, or do I go?
我下去
I'm going.
快点！
Hurry!
有人捞游泳池的落叶吗？该捞了
Anybody skimming the pool? It needs it.
马上下去
I'm going, I'm going.
我上一下洗手间
I'm going to the bathroom.
好啦，马上去
I'm going.
真是的
Damd
- 你已装卫星天线吗？ - 没有
我住的地方- -
- 你家电视有几个频道？ - 大概4、50个吧
你上过所谓资讯高速公路吗？
Are you on the information superhighway?
没有
No, not yet.
我家那边有一流的有线电视服务 总共有2千8百个频道
Where I live, with all the premium services, I get 2,800 channels.
2千8百个频道？
2,800 channels!
- 开玩笑 - 如果我愿意，我可以…
- 2,800. - No kidding.
- 哈利辛 - 要吓死人啊！
Harry Zimm. Jesus Christ!
你好吗？我叫智利帕玛
How you doing? I'm Chili Palmer.
妈啊！如果我心脏病发作 希望你知道怎么急救
Oh, Jesus. If I have a heart attack, I hope you know what to do.
你跑哪去了，哈利？
Where you been, Harry?
我们认识吗？我没印象
Have we met? I don't recall.
刚认识啦 我跟你说我叫智利帕玛
We just did. I told you my name's Chili Palmer.
你是做电影的，对吧？
You're in pictures, right?
你有没有想想 万一我心脏病发作怎么办？
Did you think what would happen if I had a heart attack?
看着我，哈利
Look at me, Harry.
我在看你啊
I am.
我要你一直看着我
Keep looking at me. Right here.
我正在看啊
That's what I'm doing.
你认识迪克亚伦吧？梅沙赌场？
You know Dick Allen? Mesa's Casino?
原来是这么回事 你是那家该死赌场的讨债人
That's what this is. You're a collector for the fucking casino.
三更半夜跑进来…
You come in here in the middle of the night...
我还以为你是想试镜的演员呢
I thought you were an actor auditioning, for chrissakes.
你看我怎么处理
We'll see about this.
总机，接洛杉矶查号台
Operator, let me have Las Vegas--
我给你一个建议
Harry, let me give you some advice.
不要装硬汉 你只穿内裤站在那里
Don't act like a hard-on. You're standing in your undies.
你应该坐下来好好跟我谈
You want to do sit and talk to me.
借条就好比支票…
Harry, a marker is like a check.
我知道何谓借条
I know what a marker is.
他们不想让你跳票 那样相当麻烦
They don't want yours to bounce. That annoys them.
我朋友迪克打很多次电话找你
Your dear friend, Dick Allen...
也留话给你了，但你都不回电
left messages on your machine, and you haven't called back.
所以他请我帮忙找你
So he asked me to look you up.
我跟你来到这里 在窗口看见你跟一个女人
So I follow you here, and I see you in a window with a woman.
她好像是“怪谭”的女演员 凯伦芙萝莉
Looks like Karen Flores, the actress from 'Grotesque.'
你没看着我
You're not looking at me, Harry.
- 为什么我要一直看着你？ - 因为我要你看着我
- Why must I look at you? - Because I want you to.
你想动粗是吧？
You're going to get rough?
我最好明天付款 不然你要打断我的腿？
I make good by tomorrow, or you'll break my legs?
拜托，哈利，梅沙要讨债的
Come on, Harry. Mesa's?
跟迪克亚伦说
You tell Dick Allen...
最多再60天 我会付清借款的
I'll cover those markers in the next 60 days.
接不接受是他的自由，那个杂碎
If he doesn't like it, that's his problem. The fucking prick.
要我帮你叫计程车吗？
So you want me to call you a cab?
你在拍电影对不对？
You make movies?
我拍电影，不拍电视
I produce feature motion pictures. No TV.
你刚刚不是提到“怪谭”  ？
You mentioned 'Grotesque' before?
凯伦芙萝莉演的是“怪谭2”
That happens to be 'Grotesque, Part II' that Karen Flores was in.
她演过三部我的“异形怪物”
She also starred in three of my 'Slime Creatures' releases.
你可能看过
You may have seen them.
我有个拍电影的点子
I got an idea for a movie.
有个家伙叫里欧
Leo, he would wear...
在迈阿密大夏天 还能戴彩格羊毛帽
plaid wool hats in Miami in the middle of summer.
他不希望被人知道他秃头
He doesn't want anyone to think he's bald.
搞什么鬼！
What the fuck？
跟智利帕玛打个招呼
Say hello to Chili Palmer.
智利，这位是凯伦芙萝莉
Chili, this is Karen Flores.
- 很高兴认识你，凯伦 - 你怎么进来的？
It's a pleasure to meet you. How'd you get in the house?
他刚跟我说一部电影的点子 到目前为止还不错
He just told me an idea for a movie. It's not bad so far.
坐下，喝一杯 跟凯伦说，听听她的想法
Sit down, have a drink. Tell Karen. See what she thinks.
你可能没听懂我的意思
Maybe you didn't hear me.
我从后门进来的
I came in the back door.
- 破门而入？ - 门开着的，没锁
- You broke in. - It was open. Wasn't locked.
- 如果有锁呢？ - 你要不要听他的点子？
- What if it were? - Want to hear the idea?
一个做干洗的 骗了航空公司30万
It's about a dry cleaner that scams the airline out of 300 grand.
- 跟她说 - 很简单
Tell her. Well, it's simple.
基本上 这家伙欠高利贷1万5千元
Basically, it's about a guy who owes a shylock $15,000...
拖了大约3个星期…
and he's three weeks over on the vig.
- 我说的是该付的利息 - 我知道
The interest you have to pay.
总之，这个做干洗的… 我们就叫他里欧吧
I know. Anyway, this dry cleaner-- Let's call him Leo.
他怕了 他不知道怎么办，于是决定落跑
He's scared. He doesn't know any better. He leaves town.
他去坐飞机 但他上了飞机，飞机却不动
So Leo gets on a plane, but the plane sits there. Doesn't move.
广播说飞机机械出了点问题
They announce there's some kind of mechanical problem.
要求旅客在座位上 等大约一个小时
They'll be there maybe an hour...
或许很快就能修好
but keep your seats, in case they fix it sooner.
这家伙很紧张根本坐不住 他很害怕
The guy's in no shape to sit there, sweat it out.
所以就下了飞机
So he gets off the plane.
他跑去机场鸡尾酒餐厅 酒一杯接一杯的喝
He goes to the cocktail lounge and starts throwing them down.
结果，飞机起飞时坠毁 而他人还在鸡尾酒餐厅
In fact, he's still in the lounge when the plane crashes on takeoff.
当他知道他的飞机坠毁时 他还不敢相信
When the guy finds out it was his flight, he can't believe it.
如果他留在飞机上他就死了
If he had stayed on the plane, he'd be dead.
现在他知道他的运气改变了
He knows his luck has changed.
如果大家认为他死了
If everybody thinks he's dead,
他就可以不必还钱了 那1万5本金和利息
he won't have to pay back the 15 or the vig.
继续说，快
Keep going. Come on.
因为里欧的名字在旅客名单上
Since Leo's name was on the passenger list...
他们请他太太到机场认尸
they bring his wife out to the airport.
大家靠一些没烧掉的物品指认
They're going through personal effects, whatever wasn't burned up.
里欧的行李还在飞机上 他太太跟他们说
Leo's bags were on the plane. The wife tells them what to look for--
她只认得一样他的东西
things that only she would know about.
噢，我的里欧！
My Leo!
几天后 航空公司的人去找他太太
A couple days go by. The airline people visit his wife.
他们向她表达最大的歉意 并提供一笔赔偿金…
They tell her they're sorry their plane exploded and offer her a settlement.
以他开干洗店一辈子 可能赚的钱作为计算基础
The amount based on what he would have earned for the rest of his life.
他老婆可以拿到多少钱？
How much is she offered?
30万，所以他们就收下了 白花花的现金耶
300 grand. So they take it. Money in their hand, babe.
他太太将支票兑现
He gets his wife to cash the check...
他带着钱到了拉斯维加斯
and he takes off for Vegas with the dough.
到了以后他应该打电话给她
He gets there. He's supposed to call her...
告诉她什么时候也过去
to let her know when to come out.
她一直没接到消息 但他手气可顺了
She never hears from him again, but he's hot.
30万一路赢到将近50万
He runs the 300 grand up to half a million.
- 然后他回到… - 可是那家伙快憋死了
- He comes to LA-- - But he's going nuts...
他赢很多钱 但不能跟别人说他是谁
because he's winning, and he can't say who he is.
我们用倒叙法 交代他想成名的动机与欲望
So we show in a back story his motivation, his desire to be famous.
他可以用钱打进社交圈
He's got the dough to buy his way in...
挤进名流圈 他无法拒绝这种诱惑
mix with the celebs, and he can't resist...
于是来到洛杉矶
so he comes to LA.
名流圈这段我不知道
I don't know about the mixing with the celebrities.
是你新加进来的
That was something new that was just added.
没错，他来到了洛杉矶
But, yeah, he comes to LA and...
以后的事我就不知道了
I don't know what happens after that.
什么？就这样？ 这就是你的电影？
What? That's it? That's your movie?
我说我有个拍电影的点子
I said that I had an idea for a movie.
这只是半部充满漏洞的电影
That's half a movie with holes in it.
或许放映出来只有40分钟
There's maybe 40 minutes of screen time.
里面没有女的…女主角
You don't have a girl, a female lead.
更重要的是 没有一个值得同情的人
On top of that, you don't have anybody to sympathize with.
- 一个好人 - 放高利贷的是个好人
- You don't have a good guy. - The shylock is a good guy.
放高利贷的戏份不够
The shylock is barely mentioned...
他老婆赔款太轻松取得 没有可信度
and it's not believable the wife would get a settlement that fast.
哈利不知道这是真实故事
Harry doesn't realize it's a true story.
迈阿密坠机事件 新闻整整报导了一个星期
That Miami flight went down? It was on the news every day for a week.
哈利一定很忙
Harry must've been busy.
- 你的点子是这样来的？ - 一部份，对啊
- That's where you got the idea? - Part of it, yeah.
你不是那个做干洗的吧？
Wait a minute. You're not the guy? The dry cleaner?
如果你是，你不可能跟我说
Leo. You wouldn't be talking to me if you were.
- 我不是那个家伙 - 但你是赌场的人？
- No, I'm not the guy, Harry. - But you work for the casino?
我的天啊，哈利！ 他是那个放高利贷的
For God's sake, Harry, he's the shylock.
是吗？你靠那行业维生？
That's what you do for a living?
我前阵子的确是做那行
That's what I did until recently.
这件事结束后 我不知道接下来要做什么
After I'm done here, I don't know what I'll do next.
我明天要出早班
I got an early call.
没关系，你上去睡吧
No problemo, babe. Go on up to bed.
我的意思是说 你和你的新朋友可以请便了
I'm saying that I would like you and your new buddy out of my house.
好啊，没问题
Oh, yeah. Well, sure.
真的非常高兴认识你，凯伦
It was absolutely a pleasure to meet you, Karen.
我猜干你这行的 有时候还是得玩狠的，对吧？
I guess in your line of work there's times you have to get rough.
如果你的客户不付钱的话？
You know, in case one of your customers don't pay?
他们都乖乖付钱
They always pay.
是吗？你有带枪？
You pack a gun?
可以说没有
Not really.
你曾被捕吗？
You ever been arrested?
曾因为放高利贷 和敲诈勒索被逮，但不曾被定罪
I've been picked up for loan-sharking and racketeering but never convicted.
- 我没前科 - 敲诈勒索…
No, I'm clean, Harry. Racketeering.
范围很广不是吗？
That covers a lot of ground, doesn't it?
说重点，哈利 你要我帮什么忙
Get to the point. You want me to do something for you.
（小巨人拿破仑 现正上映）
我们的班机到了
That's us.
乖女孩
Good girl.
不要跟我说话 坐下来假装你在等人
Don't say nothing. Sit down and act like you're waiting for somebody to meet you.
你在说什么？ 没有人知道我在这里
What the fuck you talking about? Ain't nobody know me here.
- 钱给我 - 坐下
- Give me the fucking money. - Sit down.
眼睛放亮点
Now, be looking.
你右边那个穿蓝毛衬衫的 一副没事的样子…
Man over to your right in the blue wool shirt. The other way.
另一边啦
Derecho.
他是联邦干员 很可能是缉毒组的
That's a federal officer. Most likely DEA.
脚动的时候 看到凸起来的东西吧
He moves his leg, you look for the bulge.
看到了吗？
Savvy bulge?
很好 那是他的备用枪
Good. That's his backup piece.
尽量不要直接朝他看
Try it without looking right at him. If you can.
- 你叫什么名字？ - 亚佑波提洛
- What's your name? - Yayo Portillo.
好啦，亚佑，别管他了
All right. You know he's there. Forget about him.
我马上会站起来 我一离开你就坐我的位置
I'm gonna get up. Once I'm gone, sit in the seat I'm in.
你会感觉有东西 那是保管箱的钥匙
You feel something under your ass. That's a key...
你的50万就在里面
to a locker where your half million is...
还有一些我们退回的货
along with some product we're returning.
掺了太多杂质 简直变婴儿食品了
Powder's been stepped on so many times, it's baby food.
你应该亲手把钱交给我
You're supposed to give me the money yourself!
别紧张，亚虎
Try to be cool, Yahoo.
我跟你说过在哪里
I told you where it is.
照我的话去做 保证平安无事回家去
Do it how I told you, and have a safe trip home.
你早餐吃什么？
What'd you have for breakfast?
你怎么这么重？
How come you weigh so much?
吃墨西哥面饼卷吗？
Did you have a burrito?
给那位女士，乖
Give it to the nice lady. There you go.
抱歉
Sorry
巧克力沾得到处都是
Say thank you.
说谢谢，拜拜
Thank you.
像瑞士钟表一样精准，不是吗？
Like fucking clockwork, huh, Bear?
嗨，阿波
Hi, Bo!
- 要不要去兜风，亲爱的？ - 好
Hey, Farrah. You ready to go for a ride, sweetie?
在我女儿旁边嘴巴干净一点
Told you to watch your mouth around my daughter.
白线区域仅供上下货
（马丁威尔饰拿破仑）
我的投资人经营礼车公司
These guys, my investors, they run a limo service.
开始时他们来找我 投资一些钱拍了几部电影
They put some money in a few of my pictures.
票房还不错，他们很高兴
Did okay. They're happy.
这件事发生在几个月前
This was a few months ago
也就是我开始计划 我的下一部电影时
when I was planning my next picture...
一帮杀人狂隐身在马戏团里 旅行全国各地
about this band of killer circus freaks
所到之处总是发生命案
leaving bodies in their wake.
有一个700磅重的女人
There's a 700-pound fat lady
对勾引男人很拿手 把他们带回她的拖车屋里
who has a way of seducing guys in her trailer.
哈利，看着我
Harry, look at me.
你想跟我说 你捅了大纰漏，但不是你的错
You're trying to tell me you fucked up without sounding stupid...
我没那么好骗
and that's hard to do.
我们来谈谈你的处境
Let's talk about where you're at, okay?
礼车公司那些人的钱
You blew 200 grand of these limo guys' money...
被你在维加斯赌足球输了20万 你没告诉他们，为什么？
on a football game in Vegas, and you didn't tell them. Why?
他们不是那种可能谅解你 而且行为有所节制的人
They don't seem like they'd take it with any understanding.
他们二话不说先打断你的腿再说
They'd break my legs.
既然你都知道了，如果你害怕 为什么带钱去维加斯？
You got that on the brain. If you were so scared, why go to Vegas?
我需要50万买剧本
I needed a half-million dollars to buy a script.
电影剧本
A movie script?
保证叫好又叫座 不拍变种人或疯子
Blockbuster but quality. No mutants or maniacs.
一定成为我的代表作
This is going to be my 'Driving Miss Daisy.'
墨瑞沙佛林 我“怪谭”系列电影的作者…
Murray Saffrin, the guy who wrote it, did all my 'Grotesque' pictures.
将这部剧本珍藏了20年
Had it in his drawer for 20 years.
他拿给我看时还跟我说 有一个大明星有兴趣
He shows it to me. Says he's got a major star interested.
- 我有没有兴趣当制片？ - 哪个明星？
- Would I produce it? - Which star?
获得两次奥斯卡提名的马丁威尔
Two-time Academy Award nominee, Martin Weir.
马丁威尔啊
That's Martin Weir.
就是“狂风暴”里 演向警方告密那个黑道兄弟
He played the mob guy turned snitch in 'Cyclone.'
他的代表作之一
One of his best parts.
他的最佳演出是饰演一个 登上惠特尼山的跛脚的同性恋
His best was when he played the crippled gay guy that climbed Mount Whitney.
“登上云端”  ，好电影
'Ride the Clouds.' Good picture.
- 那女人好眼熟 - 她是位摇滚明星
- That woman. She looks familiar. - She's a rock star.
他们每天同一时间来吃早餐
Every day, same time, they have breakfast.
他朝西，方便看他的电影看板
He faces west, so he can see his billboard.
她朝东，才有理由戴太阳眼镜
She faces east as an excuse to wear her shades.
- 夸张 - 总之，墨瑞的心理医生
Unbelievable. Anyway, Murray has this shrink...
正好是马丁健身教练的心理医生
who happens to be Martin's personal trainer's shrink.
墨瑞将剧本交给那个心理医生
Murray gives the shrink the script.
心理医生将它拿给 马丁的健身教练
The shrink gives it to the trainer,
他在健身时念给马丁听
who reads it to Martin.
- 马丁很喜欢，他翻过身来 - 那有什么问题？
- Martin loves it. He flips. - What's the problem?
问题出在墨瑞 他心脏病发作
The problem is Murray. Heart attack.
墨瑞的寡妇陶莉丝
Doris, Murray's widow...
发现马丁威尔这段插曲 因为墨瑞和我从不签合约
finds out about the Martin Weir thing, and as Murray and I had no contract...
她为剧本开价50万
she wants half a million for the script.
所以你希望我把你 介绍给那个做干洗的
So you want me to put you with my dry cleaner...
说服他投资你的电影
so he can invest in your movie?
对，因为我担心 万一沙佛林寡妇
That, or what if some tragic accident...
发生什么意外怎么办？
were to befall the Widow Saffrin?
不，我不会杀她
I'm not going to pop her, okay?
- 我只是刚好想起这件事 - 我跟你讲我会怎么做
It was just a thought.
我可以去找礼车公司那些人 叫他们暂时不要逼你
I'll meet with these limo guys-- tell them to leave you alone for a while.
我会设法让他们听得进去
Make the point so they understand.
你不了解他们那些人
You don't know these guys.
相信我，我比你了解他们多了
Believe me, Harry. I know them better than you do.
（安杰琳）
（辛制片公司）
我问过一个文字经纪人 哪种文字可以卖最多钱
I once asked a literary agent what kind of writing paid best.
他说赎金通知
He said, 'Ransom notes.'
这就是啦- -  “勒夫乔伊先生”
Ransom notes. Here it is, 'Mr.Lovejoy.'
（我跟外太空来的盗墓者结婚）
“勒夫乔伊坐在驾驶座上 观察对街的酒吧
'Lovejoy sits behind the wheel watching a bar, getting his video camera--'
进入他的摄影机里…”
Is he following someone?
- 他在跟踪某人？ - 往下看，很精彩
Read it. It's a grabber.
你的投资人来了
I think your investors are here.
- 我的妈呀 - 这是我的计划
Oh, Jesus. All right, this is the plan.
我让礼车公司那些人坐椅子 不是坐沙发，听清楚了？
I want the limo guys to sit in the chairs. Got that?
嗯
Year
不，百叶窗开着 我希望光线照他们的眼睛
Keep the blinds open. I want the light in their eyes.
我坐桌子后面 不需要介绍我
I'll sit at the desk. Don't introduce me.
直接跟他们谈，他们坐下后 你站在他们后面，懂吗？
Just start talking, and stand behind them as they sit. You understand?
他们会看着你 但他们不知道你是谁
They'll be looking at you, but they don't know who you are.
他们会问“这家伙是谁？”
They'll be saying, 'Who is this guy?'
什么都别说 别告诉他们我是谁
But don't say anything. Do not tell them who I am.
- 我得跟他们说点什么吧 - 不，不要说话
- I gotta say something. - No, you don't.
不该说的不要说
Don't say more than you have to.
除非你想说
Unless it's like...
比如“很高兴你们几个废料前来 我干脆有话直说”
'Glad you assholes stopped by. Now I can straighten you out.'
开什么玩笑？
You're kidding, right?
说电影延后一年 不要告诉他们原因
Just say the movie's been postponed a year but not why.
不管说什么 不要提到“勒夫乔伊先生”
Whatever you do, don't mention 'Mr.Lovejoy.' Got that?
好啦，准备
Let's go.
- 嘿，隆尼 - 哈利，嗨
- Hey, Ronnie. - Hey, Harry. Hi.
哇！这是什么年代？
- Bo. - Wow! What year is it?
我们进入了时光隧道吗？ 感觉来到了好莱坞的昨日世界
Did we enter a time warp? I feel like I'm in Hollywood of yesteryear.
- 那边请坐 - 好
Have a seat.
我同事智利帕玛 往后他会帮我一些忙
This is my associate, Chili Palmer. He'll be working with me.
我们应该没什么误会
So there's no misunderstanding...
尽管你可能听到一些谣言
in spite of the rumors you might have heard...
你对“怪谭”的投资 跟签合资合约时一样没问题
your investment in 'Freaks' is solid as the day you signed... your participation agreement.
我听得到你，但你躲在哪里？
I can hear you, man, but where are you?
这里啊
Right here.
我搞不懂他躲哪去了？
What I've been wondering is, 'Where's he been?'
对啊，你去哪，哈利？ 最近都没有你的消息
Where you been? We haven't heard from you lately.
去纽约，找演员、勘景
New York. I was interviewing actors, scouting locations.
主要是“怪谭”将会 延后几个月
Main thing is 'Freaks' is going to be delayed a couple months.
- 几个月？ - 对
- A couple months? - Yeah.
只要几个月 需要再…
Just a couple months. We need more...
筹备一段时间
prep.
乱搞，我们有签合约的
Bullshit, man! We have an agreement with you.
我们要拍这部电影
We are going to do this picture.
我们要拍这部电影 另外有一部片要先拍…
I just have another project to do first.
我已经答应一个人很多年了
One I promised this guy for years.
我要看你的帐册，哈利
I want to see your books.
帐册在哪里… 我们投资的20万
Show me a two with five zeros after it.
我要看帐
In black and white. I want to see your books.
我要看银行报表
I want to see your fucking bank statements.
嘿，隆尼，看着我
Hey, Ronnie. Look at me.
你们投资的是一部电影 不是哈利身体的某一部份
You have a piece of a movie, not a piece of Harry.
如果他今年想拍另一部片 他当然可以那么做
If he wants to do another movie this year, that's how it's gonna be.
抱歉，兄弟 你是什么东西？
Excuse me, bro', but who the fuck are you?
正在向你解释的人
I'm telling you how it is.
凯勒特
Catlett
你们要先拍的是什么电影？
What is this other movie you're doing for us?
- 我跟你… - 哈利，我会回答这个问题
- Let me show you. - Let me answer this one.
先说清楚，我该跟谁谈… 跟他还是跟你？
Who am I talking to? Him or you?
你可以跟我谈
You can talk to me.
我也这么想 这样说好了
That's what I thought. Let me put it this way.
除了“怪谭”之外 我们做什么不关你屁事
Outside of 'Freaks,' it's none of your business what we do.
噢！在这里 这就是那个计划 “勒夫乔伊先生”
Here it is right here. This is the project. 'Mr.Lovejoy.'
我不希望你以为 我随便拿点东西唬你们
I don't want you to think I'm putting something over on you.
“勒夫乔伊先生” 是啥玩意，色情片？
'Mr.Loveboy.' What is it, a porno flick?
很复杂的电影，你不会有兴趣的
It's fluff. You wouldn't be interested in it.
你以为我们会看你的电影？ 牙齿的X光底片还比较好看
You think we see your movies? I've seen better film on teeth.
投资哪一部片都一样
It makes no difference to me which one our money's in.
从“怪谭”抽出百分之20
Take our 20 points out of 'Freaks'...
- 投资这部“勒夫乔伊先生” - 不，不行
and put them in this 'Mr.Loverboy.' No, I can't do that.
你确定？
You're positive?
对，条件不一样 已经…谈定了
It's a different kind of deal. It's structured.
好吧 你可以把钱还给我们
Okay. Then be good enough to hand us our money back...
或者考虑让我们加入这部新片 想好让我们知道
or you think about us coming in on this new deal. Let us know.
星期五，不然你就死定了 听清楚了吧？
By Friday, or you're fucking dead as disco. You hear me?
慢慢考虑，哈利 我们不是禽兽
Take your time, Harry. We're not animals.
对吧，隆尼？
Are we, Ronnie?
（辛制片公司）
什么？
What?
What!
我可能说得不够清楚 但我跟你说过，叫你闭嘴不谈
Maybe I wasn't clear, but I thought I told you to keep your mouth shut.
总得跟他们交代一下吧
I had to tell them something.
哈利，没有必要的话不要说
Never say anything unless you have to.
你要我帮你甩掉这帮人
You asked me to get these guys off your back.
结果却变成 “来分’勒夫乔伊先生’一杯羹”
Next thing I know, you're saying, 'Have a piece of 'Mr.Lovejoy.''
我简直不敢相信我的耳朵
I couldn't believe my ears.
我跟他们说我考虑考虑
I told them I'd think about it.
在我们这里，那有什么意义？ 空话一句
In this town, what does that mean? Nothing.
这就是你跟我不一样的地方
That's the difference between you and me, Harry.
我不说空话
I say what I mean.
如果想跟某人要某样东西 我会跟他们直说
If I want something from someone, I ask them.
如果要马丁威尔 我会直接找马丁威尔
If I want Martin Weir, I go get Martin Weir.
我不会跟他的健身教练的 心理医生瞎搅和
I don't fuck around with his trainer's shrink.
- 是心理医生的健身教练 - 送我到我车子那
Shrink's trainer. Take me back to my car.
- 喂？你跑去哪里？ - 我是汤米，阿智
- Tommo? Chili. - Where you been?
到处打电话都找不到你
I been calling all over for you.
雷朋斯在找你，你死哪去了？
Ray Bones is looking for you. Where the hell are you?
- 现在在洛杉矶 - 你去那里干嘛？
- I'm in LA now. - What are you doing out there?
我要进入电影圈 正在考虑要当制片
Going into the movie business. I'm thinking about producing.
电影制作你懂个屁啊？
What the fuck do you know about making movies?
制片不需要懂太多
I don't think the producer has to know much.
你说的要不是屁话就是呆话
I think you're full of shit.
我得挂断了
I gotta go.
等你了解雷朋斯多一点后 再打电话给我
Call me when you know more about Ray Bones.
凯伦，你好吗？
- Hey, Chili-- - Karen, how you doing?
你又来干嘛？
What are you doing here?
我来向你道歉的 因为昨晚破门而入
I wanted to apologize for breaking in last night.
这是什么道理
Let me get this straight.
你破门而入来 为前次破门而入道歉？
You broke in again to apologize for breaking in before?
不，你阳台门开着
Your patio door was open.
你应该锁门 你家里好东西不少
You shouldn't do that. You got nice things in here.
出去时记得锁门
Make sure you lock it on the way out.
今天过得不顺吗？
Bad day?
花了一整天努力爬出墓穴
I spent all day crawling out of a grave.
导演说我根本没办法
The director said I was incapable of reaching...
进入角色的感情核心
the emotional core of the character.
什么？显然他没看过 你的“变种人新娘”
What? Obviously he didn't see you in 'Bride of the Mutant.'
你看过？
You saw that?
当你转过头面对镜头
When you turn to the camera...
跟异形妈妈说 她在地球的日子结束时
and say to the alien mother that her time on Earth is finished...
就算琼克萝馥在巅峰时期 也会希望她当年的演出
Joan Crawford, on her best day, wished that she had had...
有你在那场戏里表达的 感情和张力
in her day, the intensity you had in that scene.
那场戏还不错啦… 我的意思是以恐怖电影来说
That was a good scene. I mean, for a horror movie.
不，以任何标准来看都是
For any movie.
我知道我不只如此
I'm better than what I've been doing...
不是胸大无脑 只会时间一到就尖叫而已
wearing fuck-me pumps and a tank top, waiting 'til it was time to scream.
- 但你叫得很好听 - 对，那是我天生的本钱
But what a scream. It's a real gift.
我的意思是，如果有机会说一句 伟大的台词也很棒
All I'm saying is it'd be nice to get the chance to say one great line.
好比贝蒂戴维斯 在“棉田小屋”里
Like in that great Bette Davis movie, 'Cabin in the Cotton'...
她走向一个用眼光挑逗她的人
where she walks up to the guy, gives him a look...
说道“我愿意给你一个吻 但我刚洗过头”
and says, 'I'd kiss you, but I just washed my hair.'
好台词，你怎么 不拍哈利的电影了？
Great line. How come you don't do movies with Harry anymore?
因为我嫁给伟大的马丁威尔 他要的全职老婆
Because I married the great Martin Weir. He was a full-time job.
- 你看过哈利的新剧本吗？ - 没有
Have you read Harry's new script?
他说那是他看过最棒的剧本
He says it's the best thing he's ever read.
他应该是说“异形怪物3”之后
He must mean after 'Slime Creatures III.'
所以哈利昨晚过来…
Was that why Harry came over last night?
请你帮他说服马丁拍一部电影？
To ask you to help him put Martin in a movie?
哈利梦想拍一部4千万的电影
Harry's dreaming up a $40 million production
他根本拍不成
he'll get off the ground...
不管我帮不帮他 他都签不下一个大明星
with a star he'll never sign, with or without my help.
- 他说马丁对剧本非常有兴趣 - 马丁对任何东西都很有兴趣
He said Martin flipped over it. Martin's known for his flipping.
他对剧本表现很大的兴趣 等到要谈条件时他就想脱身了
He flips over a script, then before the deal, he flips out.
我到哈利办公室拿一份剧本给你
Why don't I go to Harry's office and get a copy of the script?
你先看看再说？
Read it yourself. See what you think.
不用麻烦了
Don't go out of your way.
不，一点都不麻烦
No, it's nothing.
我要去跟我那个落跑的 干洗店老板里欧谈谈了
I better go talk to Leo, my runaway dry cleaner.
对，看你的故事该怎么结尾
Right. See how your story ends.
我住的饭店附近 在上演“历劫佳人”
That movie, 'Touch of Evil,' is playing near my hotel.
如果你愿意，我们可以去看… 却尔登希斯顿饰演墨西哥人
We could check it out if you want. Watch Charlton Heston be a Mexican.
没关系，下次吧
That's all right. Another time.
回头见
See you around.
再见
See you.
嗨，我叫雷 智利帕玛的朋友
My name is Ray. I'm a friend of Chili Palmer's.
你丈夫出事后 你跟帕玛先生说过话吗？
Have you spoken with Mr.Palmer since your husband blew up?
一、二次
Once or twice.
你们谈些什么？
What was it you talked about?
没什么，东聊西聊
Nothing, really. This and that.
东聊西聊？
This and that?
我真的很想跟你当朋友
I really want us to be friends.
如非真的必要，朋友之间 不会彼此殴打
And we know that friends don't hit each other unless they have to.
所以我们重来一次你觉得如何
Let's start all over again...
你跟我说清楚到底发生什么事
and you tell me exactly what the fuck is going on.
怎么样？好不好？
Okay?
晚安，先生
Good evening, sir.
你也晚安，先生
And a very good evening to you, too, sir.
谢谢
Thank you.
里欧…
Leo.
看着我
Look at me.
没想到你这么笨
I never thought you'd be so dumb.
30几万藏在衣橱里 只用张毯子盖着
Leaving over 300 grand in the closet under a blanket.
可是你真的就这么笨
But I guess you are.
我不知道该藏在哪里
I didn't know where else to keep it.
你会藏哪里？
Where would you?
银行怎么样？
How about a bank?
不，他们会向国税局打小报告
They'd report it to the IRS.
你不必开户 只要放在保险箱里
Don't open an account. Put in it a safe-deposit box.
想用时就去拿
You dip in it whenever you want.
你怎么知道我在这里？
How'd you know I was here?
再告诉你一个小秘诀
Here's another tip.
下次写信给你老婆 不要用饭店的信笺
Next time you write your wife, don't use hotel stationery.
钱的事是费告诉你的对吗？
Fay told you about the money?
她把我从小到大 任何事情都告诉你了？
She tell you my whole life story?
- 里欧，我是来救你的 - 怎么救？把我的钱拿走？
I'm here to save your ass. How? By taking my money?
不，你赢来的钱你留着 那是你的
The money you won today is yours.
全都是我的
It's all mine!
里欧，坐下
Leo, sit down.
我不知道你为什么这么厉害 你实在很笨
I don't know how you got this far. You're so fucking dumb.
但现在结束了 我跟你解释为什么
You're through. I'm gonna explain why.
希望你不会笨到听不懂
I hope you're not so dumb that you won't understand.
对付你的人是雷朋斯
Ray Bones is the man you're dealing with now.
当朋斯知道你干的事 他会把你所有财产都抢走
When he finds out what you did, he'll take everything...
包括你头上那顶可爱的帽子
including the sporty little hat you got on your head.
最可能的是，他会杀你灭口
Most likely he'll shoot you, so you won't tell on him.
我不会这么做，我不会伤害你
I'm not gonna do that. I'm not gonna hurt you.
你的袋子里有31万
You've got $310,000 in the bag here.
你从航空公司A来的30万我带走 剩下的1万
I'll take the 300 you scammed from the airlines, and the 10 leftover...
算我跟你借 以后会还你
I'll borrow from you and pay back at another time.
等等
Wait.
钱全部被你拿走 只有一部份算是借的？
You take all my money, but you're borrowing part of it?
利息18% 不要再问问题，我要走了
At 18%. Now, don't ask another fucking question. I'm leaving now.
但你不知道我在哪里 连我都不知道自己会去哪里
You won't know where I am! I don't even know where I'll be!
我会找你，里欧 你走过的地方都会留下痕迹
I'll find you, Leo. You leave a trail like a fucking caterpillar.
嘿
Hey
等一下，18%利息先说清楚
Wait a minute. What's this 18%-a-year shit?
你借了1万 每个星期利息就是300元
You want to borrow 10, the vig is 3 bills a week.
利息一共1万5加上本金1万 连本带利共计2万5
That's 15 for the vig plus the 10. That's 25 big ones!
说好了借一整年哦！
You go the whole year, buddy!
听到没？
You hear me!
（市场）
（熟食店）
太棒了
This is good.
这部“勒夫乔伊先生” 的结局还不够好
This 'Mr.Lovejoy.'
但真精彩，现在我知道 为什么哈利想拍这部片
It needs a better ending, but yes, I can see why Harry wants to do it.
我知道哈利在撒谎 一边说剧本不好一边又巴着不放
You understand. I knew Harry was lying, saying this wasn't any good...
一副非得把他的手指打断 他才肯放手的样子
but holding on to it like you'd have to break his fingers to get it from him.
奇怪
That's funny.
我心里正在想我该打断 你哪个部位你才肯放手？
I was thinking what I'll have to break to get it away from you.
我来跟你解释我想干嘛 免得你以为我来闯空门
I'm explaining to you what I'm doing here in case you thought...
想偷这些不值钱的东西
I came to rip off any of this dusty old shit that the man has.
看你的穿着，我不会把你当小偷
I wouldn't make you out to be a burglar. Not in that outfit.
哈利叫你合伙人 那是什么意思？
Harry called you his associate. What does that mean?
我没听过你的名字
I never heard your name
也没在好莱坞报导 或综艺周刊看过你的名字
or read it in the 'Hollywood Reporter' or 'Variety.'
他说得很清楚，我是他合伙人
What he said. I'm his associate.
你对这个案子一定有重大贡献
You must bring something heavy to the deal.
的确- - 那就是我
I do. Me.
听说你可以邀请马丁威尔 来饰演勒夫乔伊？
It says here you're getting Martin Weir for the part of Lovejoy?
没错，我们要请马丁
That's right. Martin.
我不信 你打算怎么请？
Come on. How you gonna do that?
我会拿把枪指着他的脑袋
I'm gonna put a gun to his head and say...
说“签字，马丁，不然就没命” 就这样
'Sign the fucking papers, Martin, or you're dead.' That's it.
我怀疑这招有效吗？
I wonder, would that work?
你知道我认为谁适合 演艾尔罗西吗？
You know who I see for the part of Al Roxy?
哈维凯托 简直是为他量身订做的
Harvey Keitel. Man could play it in his sleep.
他在“手指”里的演出很精彩
He was pretty good in the movie 'Fingers.'
没看过 你知道还有谁适合吗？
Missed it.
摩根费里曼 摩根的电影你熟吗？
You know who else? Morgan Freeman. You know his work?
摩根费里曼，但他是黑人
Morgan Freeman, yeah. But he's a colored guy.
那又怎么样？
So what?
剧本里有说他是白人吗？
Where's it say in the script the man's got to be white?
这个角色需要加点颜色 演这个角色的人要有特殊风格
Color's what the part needs, man. Somebody to do it with some style.
你觉得剧本怎么样？
What do you think of the script?
（辛制片公司）
首先，片名要改
First thing that's got to go is the title.
用编剧的名字墨瑞沙佛林 都比勒夫乔伊好
The writer's name, Murray Saffrin, would be better than Lovejoy.
这点我同意
I'm with you on that one.
你知道我有什么主意吗？
You know what I'm thinking?
我们两个好好坐下来 剧本写不好的地方，我们来改写
Why don't you and I rewrite the script where it needs it?
你会写剧本？
You could write one?
写剧本有什么了不起
There's nothing to it.
先想好点子 再把它写在纸上
All you do, you get an idea. Set down what you want to say on paper.
然后请一个枪手 在正确的地方补上逗点等等符号
Then you hire someone else to fill in the commas and shit...
如果你自己不太确定的话
where they belong, if you're not positive yourself.
或许也订正一下某些艰深的字
Maybe fix up the spelling where you have some tricky words.
我看过一些剧本，里面错字连篇
Although I've seen some scripts I know the words weren't spelled right.
甚至连逗点都不用 所以我认为这不太重要
There were hardly any commas at all, so I don't think that's too important.
好啦，要结束时 你就写“淡出”然后就完成了
You get to the end. You write in, 'Fade out.' You're done.
就这样 写剧本这么简单？
That's it? That's all there is?
那我要你干嘛？
Then what the fuck do I need you for?
因为我愿意为这部片效命
Because I'm offering my services on this one.
我来跟你说 需要你效劳的时候
Tell you what. If I need a ride sometime...
我会告诉你
I'll let you know.
你怎么可以在这里逮捕我？ 这是我的国家
How could you arrest me here? This is my country.
这是你送命的地方
This is where you're going to die.
这不是点火失败 是叫你转过身来
That was no misfire! That was to turn you around...
我不想对你的背后开枪
'cause I don't want to shoot you in the back...
除非你还是选择逃跑
unless you'd rather try to run from me.
史瓦兹，她在那里吗？ 你有带我太太来吗？
Is she there? Did you bring my wife?
她在车子里 全部都录下来了
She's in the car. They've got it all on tape.
- 你确定录得够多？ - 播出来听你就知道了
- You sure you got enough? - Play it back. You'll see.
你陷害了多少人？
How many did you frame?
- 那把枪最好给我 - 好，拿去
- You better give me that gun. - Okay, here it is.
“这是我帮你挡下的 第二颗子弹”
That's the second bullet I've stopped for you. That's the second bullet I've stopped for you.
你死定了，奥森
You're going down, Orson.
不是有人该进来把他带走吗？
Isn't somebody going to come and take him away?
对，等一下 你真的喜欢他，对吧？
In a few minutes. You really liked him, didn't you?
“条子喜欢他”
The cop did.
杀他的那一个
The cop did. The one who killed him.
“他喜欢他”
- He loved him. - He loved him.
汉克算是个好侦探
He was a great detective.
“但他是很差劲的条子”
- But a lousy cop. - And a lousy cop.
你对他只有这句话？
Is that all you have to say for him?
他是个很有个性的人
He was some kind of a man.
你对他人的评语有什么作用？
What does it matter what you say about people?
再见，谭雅 再会
- Good-bye, Tanya. - Adios.
再会
Adios.
（剧终）
哇，噢？
Whoo
你一直在这里？
You've been here the whole time?
没有，刚好赶上结局
I just caught the end.
知道吗 威尔斯根本不想拍这部片
Welles didn't even want to do this movie.
但他被制片厂的合约绑住了
He had some studio contract he couldn't get out of.
有时候你拍出最好的作品 因为别人用枪抵着你的脑袋
Sometimes you do your best work when you got a gun to your head.
对
Yeah
我帮你带剧本来了
I brought the script.
我看过了，哈利留了一本在我家
Harry left a copy at my house.
- 喜欢吗？ - 并不恐怖
- How'd you like it? - It's not horrible.
我不喜欢片名和其中几个角色
I don't like the title, and I don't like some characters.
- 你看过了 - 还没，但我会看
- So you read it? - Not yet, but I will.
- 你和哈利应该会合作得很好 - 是吗？
- You and Harry make a great team. - Is that right?
- 我要跟他谈条件 - 有找到你喜欢的角色吗？
- I'll make a deal with him. - You found a role you like?
不，我不想演，我想当制作人
I don't want to act in it. I want to produce it.
- 尤其如果我帮他请到马丁的话 - 合理
- Especially if I help get Martin. - That's fair.
是啊 你有什么好处？
Yeah. So, what do you get out of it?
你特地下来问我这个问题？
Is that why you came? To ask me that?
我想知道
I want to know.
为什么有人想待在电影圈？
Why would anyone want to be in the movies?
昨天你还是个放高利贷的
Yesterday you were a loan shark.
但我不喜欢做这行
Yeah, but I was never that into it.
尤其讨厌口口声声 尊敬不尊敬的屁话
Especially this bullshit about having respect.
别提了 把他们当偶像一样对待
It's bad enough treating these guys like they're your heroes.
还要微笑面对 他们自以为有趣的评论
Smiling at stupid comments they think are so funny.
你以为电影圈不一样？
You think the movie business is any different?
但我喜欢电影
Yeah, but I like movies.
如果帮哈利制作一部电影 我可以学到
If I help Harry, I'll find out what to do...
除了筹钱之外的一些技巧
outside of raising money and having an idea.
听起来并不难
That doesn't sound so hard.
我以前是搞金融的 我脑袋里多的是想法
I was in the money business, and I have a lot of ideas floating in my head.
我明天早上跟马丁谈
Listen, I'm going to talk to Martin tomorrow morning.
我跟哈利说，谈完后 我会在阿比丘跟你们碰面
I told Harry I'd meet you and him at the Abiquiu restaurant afterwards.
可能行得通
This just might work out.
谁知道呢
You never know.
有可能
It just might.
再见
Adios.
我在机场花了8小时 观察别人身体凸起的部位
I spent eight hours at the airport looking at people's bulges.
我不喜欢那样
I don't like that.
我们做买卖不是这个样子
This is not the way we do business.
你们两个不知道对手是谁
You do not know who you are messing with.
我不要妈的钥匙，我要钱
I don't want no fucking key. I want the money.
想抽烟的话，不要站在 我一码70元的地毯上
Yayo! You gonna smoke, get the hell off my $70-a-yard carpet.
我跟你说过钱在哪里 你只要去拿就得了
I told you where the money is. All you got to do is go and get it.
不，我跟你说件事
No! Now I tell you something.
我去机场，打开保管箱 他们就会逮补我
I go to the airport, open that locker and they bust me?
我会跟他们说 我是来帮你拿东西的
I tell them I come to get something for you.
我只知道这些
That's all I know.
- 你只知道这些？ - 我只知道这些
- That's all you know? - That's all I know.
在这里等，我马上回来
Wait here a minute, Yayo. I'll be back directly.
帮我盯着雅虎
Keep an eye on Yahoo for me.
事情就应该这样办
That's how you get things done.
你拿那东西想干嘛？
What the fuck you gonna do with that?
我要宰了你，雅虎
I'm taking you out, Yahoo.
看到没，那个人就这样过去？
Did you see that? The way the man just went right over?
或许我们可以把智利帕玛带来
Maybe we could get Chili Palmer up here?
你可以安排我的栏杆垮下去 像电影里一样
You could fix my railing to give way like in the movies.
我请他上来 观赏景观
I invite the man up here to look at my view.
让他靠向栏杆…
Get him to lean over the railing...
这是我听过最笨的主意
Dumbest idea I ever heard.
我跟你说，贝尔
Here's the thing, Bear.
我想当电影制作
I want to produce movies.
如果不想从事电影业 住在洛杉矶有什么意义？
What's the point of living in LA unless you're in the movie business?
我的意思是位高权重那种
And I mean high up in it.
所以哈利得跟我一起制作 “勒夫乔伊先生”
That's why Harry's going to produce 'Mr.Lovejoy' with me...
而不是跟智利帕玛
not Chili Palmer.
我不相信这张地图是正确的
I can't believe this map is accurate.
我在日落大道花了10元 向一个小鬼买的
I bought it for ten bucks from a kid on Sunset.
我们应该在餐厅碰面
You were supposed to meet me at the restaurant.
上面说“马丁威尔家 在乔治汉弥顿家对街”
I know, but look. 'Martin Weir's house across from George Hamilton.'
那一定是乔治的…
- That must be Geo-- - Chili?
妮可？
Nicole?
天啊，是你！我现在是尼基
Jesus, it is you. It's Nicki now.
我不敢相信！
I don't believe this.
我认识她
This is great. I know her.
嗨，尼基
- Hi, Nicki. - Karen.
我没看到你在那儿，你好吗？
Shit, I didn't see you there. How are you?
来，你一定要进来 跟马丁见个面
Come in, baby. You gotta come in. You gotta meet Martin.
你去哪了？你都在做些什么？
Where've you been? What've you been doing?
智利是老莫家族 唯一不曾企图染指我的人
Chili was the only one at Momo's didn't try to hit on me.
噢，真是位绅士
What a gentleman.
喜欢我的头发吗？黑色的？
Do you like my hair? Black...
漂亮，尤其是腋毛
Nice, yeah. Especially under the arms.
马丁不让我剃掉 可能可以满足他某些需求吧
Martin won't let me shave. Guess I fill some need.
让他找回60年代的感觉
Takes him back to the sixties or something.
说曹操曹操到
Speak of the devil.
- 凯伦，你看你 - 嗨，马丁
Karen, look at you.
好香，你一向都很香
You smell so good. She always smells so good.
好极了，马丁，这位是智利帕玛
Neat. Martin, this is Chili Palmer.
- 智利？ - 幸会，马丁
- Chili, is it? - Nice to meet you, Martin.
智利是黑道 我以前在他帮另一个迈阿密黑道
Chili's a gangster.
经营的夜店表演 老莫最近好吗？
Ran a club I used to play at for another gangster back in Miami.
- 挂了 - 可怜
- How is Momo these days? - Dead.
我让你们好好聊电影的事
Bummer. Well, I'll let you get to your movie talk.
阿智，不要没说再见就走了
Chili, do not leave without saying good-bye to me.
接下来？
So...
你知道你有多漂亮吗？
You know how beautiful you are?
你真是漂亮
You really are beautiful.
我坐在这里…
I'm sitting here...
看着你，我们之间的回忆 不禁涌上心头
I'm looking at you, having memories of us.
真的？
- Really? - Yeah.
我觉得不解我们怎么会出问题？ 感情怎么消逝的？
I'm wondering, how did it go wrong? How did it all slip away?
不是消逝掉的，马丁 是你干的好事
It didn't slip away. You did,
你在我生日派对时 偷溜去跟尼基上床
by going off to fuck Nicki at my birthday party.
那个派对真是不错
Yeah. That was a good party.
马帝，你在 “终极风暴”的演出真精彩
Marty, you were so good in 'The Cyclone.'
我叫马丁
Martin.
那个角色写得很好
That was a beautiful role.
我只要掌握好角色的感情核心
All I had to do was find the character's center...
只要上紧发条，他自然就演得好
the stem I used to wind him up, and he'd play.
- 他会自然而然的演 - 沉稳冷酷
- He'd just play. - You had that down cold.
要不是我了解内幕 我会以为你是黑社会大老
If I didn't know better, I'd have thought you was a made guy.
- 谢谢 - 自然挥洒，对不对？
- Thank you. - I mean, no acting there.
还有出卖兄弟那段，我的天啊
And the fink part. Oh, man. Jesus Christ!
我不曾碰到爪耙子 希望我一辈子都不会碰到
I never met a fink, and I hope I never do...
但你演的爪耙子真是出神入化
but the way you played a fink, that's how it's gotta be, right?
对
Yeah.
开拍前两个星期
Two weeks before we started shooting...
我去义大利区听你们的说话方式
I went back to Bensonhurst just to hear you guys talk.
我是义大利裔 但我在塔萨纳长大
I'm Italian, but I grew up in Tarzana.
所以我去学习你们的说话韵律
I wanted to get the rhythms of your speech, you know?
我们说话不一样吗？
We speak differently?
应该说是你们的态度和口气
It's more your attitude. Your tone.
你们的说话方式在表达意见时
Your speech patterns show a certain confidence in yourselves...
展示出一种自信 对传统观点毫不放在心上
in your opinions, your indifference to conventional views.
就好像…
It's like--
一副鸟都不鸟的样子
We don't give a shit.
有一点，没错
Kind of, yeah.
一旦我学会道地的发音方式
Anyway, once I get the authentic sounds of speech...
韵律、腔调等等
the rhythms, the patois, you know...
我就可以了解他们的想法 我可以想像他们内心的思考模式
I can actually get into their heads and think the way those guys do.
- 真的？ - 是的
- Really? - Yeah.
我是他们的一份子 我现在在想什么？
I'm one of those guys. What am I thinking?
别搞错我的意思
Don't get me wrong.
我没办法真的变一个人 不然就不叫演戏了
An actual metamorphosis doesn't take place. That wouldn't be acting.
- 所以你不知道我在想什么？ - 我不知道，但我很好奇
- So you don't know what I'm thinking? - No, but I'm curious.
你想知道我在想什么？
You want to know what I'm thinking?
- 如果你想告诉我的话 - 我在想一部电影
- Yeah, if you want to tell me. - I'm thinking about a movie.
我的电影？
One of mine?
不，我正在筹备的电影
No, one that we're producing.
用道上兄弟的钱？是吗？
With what? Wise guy money?
或许我们不该来找你
Maybe this wasn't a good idea.
不，我跟黑道脱离关系了
No, no. I'm not connected to that anymore.
不在迈阿密放高利贷之后 我就跟他们脱离关系了
Not since I left loan-sharking in Miami.
压力太大？
The pressure got too much?
压力？我是施压的人
Pressure? I'm the one who applied the pressure.
是吗？
Oh, yeah?
马丁，我可以问你一个问题吗？
- Can I ask a question? - Yeah.
你是演员，演员喜欢假装对吧？
You're an actor. Actors like to pretend.
我们的专长是让人信以为真
We've been known to make believe.
那你假装这个 你是个放高利贷的
Pretend this. You're a shylock.
有个人欠你1万5
A guy owes you 15 grand, and he skips town.
结果他落跑了，你怎么办？
He takes off. What do you do?
马丁，拜托
Oh, Martin, for chrissake.
实在有够…
Just...
我在演放高利贷的 实际上我不是
you know. I'm doing Shylock, instead of a shylock.
- 对 - 好，我的动机是什么？
- Right. - What's my motivation?
要钱，讨债
The acquisition of money. To collect.
必要时给他尝点苦头
To inflict pain if I have to.
敢A我1万5
Guy splits with 15 large of my money?
我追到他无路可逃！ 不然你认为我会怎么办？
I'd go after him! What the hell you think I'd do?
- 马丁，看着我 - 我在看你啊
- Look at me. - I am looking at you.
像我看你这样看着我
No, look at me the way I'm looking at you.
眼神最重要
Put it in your eyes.
“你跑得掉吗，猪头” 根本不必开口
'You're mine, asshole.' Without saying it.
这样怎么样？
How about this?
你在干嘛，困了吗？ 想睡觉吗？
What are you telling me? That you're sleepy? That you want to go to bed?
好，等一下
Wait, wait.
好了
Oket
挤眉弄眼，好像忘了戴眼镜
Now you're squinting, like you need glasses.
不然，你会怎样…
What do you--
- 看着我？ - 什么？
- Look at me. - What?
我心里想的是 “谅你逃不出我的手掌心”
What I'm thinking is, 'You're mine.' 'I fucking own you.'
但我不会特地去想某一件事
What I'm not doing is feeling one way or another about it.
你对我来说不是一个人
You see, you're not a person to me.
你只是我帐本里的一笔欠款 只是欠我钱的一个家伙
You're an entry in my book. A guy who owes me money.
这样怎么样？
All right. How about this?
噢，哇
Who oh
不错，不错
Not bad. Not bad.
- 难怪你是马丁威尔 - 没错
- No wonder you're Martin Weir. - Oh, yeah.
我对你的感觉就是这样，猪头
That's what I think of you, asshole.
不是个东西
Nothing.
我没话说的
I believe it. I believe it.
碰到那家伙，我就这副德行？
I turn this on when I confront the guy?
你还没找到他 他逃到拉斯维加斯去了
You haven't found him yet because he split for Las Vegas.
- 我怎么知道的？ - 他太太跟你说的
- How do I know that? - His wife told you.
他太太告诉我，好的
His wife told me. Okay.
哈利，你好吗？
Harry, how you doing?
阿波，嗨，我很好
Oh, hi. Great.
我在等人
I'm expecting some people.
谈大生意哟，在这种地方吃午饭
You must be doing some big deals, doing lunch in a place like this.
对，在忙一些事情
I'm working on a few things.
听说你搞定了马丁威尔 演你的“勒夫乔伊先生”
I hear you bagged Martin Weir for 'Mr.Lovejoy.'
这里消息传得真快
This town. Word gets around, doesn't it?
昨晚智利帕玛…
Chili Palmer told me.
打电话叫我到你办公室跟我说的
Last night, when he called me over to your office to talk about it.
智利帕玛拿我的剧本给你看？
Chili Palmer showed you my script?
对，我不懂他为什么这样做
Yeah. I was wondering why he'd do that.
他太太控告航空公司 她可不是好欺负的
So the wife sues the airline. This is some gutsy babe.
长得又漂亮…像凯伦
Good-looking too. Like Karen.
跟她丈夫碰面时 我就这副表情？
When do I meet up with the husband and give him the look?
没这么简单
That's not so simple.
另外有个凶狠的黑道，你欠他钱
There's a mob guy. Real hard-on. You owe him money.
他在找你，想把你干掉 因为你打断他的鼻子又对他开枪
He wants to take you out because you broke his nose and shot him.
很好，继续说
Right, right. Go ahead. Keep going.
目前故事就发展到此
At this point, basically that's got to be it.
你只跟我讲这些？
That's all you'll tell me?
事实上，今天找你是要谈
Actually, Martin, the reason we came by...
“勒夫乔伊先生”
was to talk about 'Mr.Lovejoy.'
我们知道你看过剧本 你表示很喜欢
We understand you read the script. You loved it. You flipped.
记不得了，给点提示
Refresh my memory.
哈利，你想不想借50万？
Listen, Harry. How'd you like to get your hands on $500,000?
不用利息，随便你什么时候还
You pay me back at your convenience with no interest.
真的？
Are you serious?
我只要求加入你这部电影
All I want in return is to work on this movie with you.
我已经有了强烈的想法 知道怎么加强剧本
I've already got some strong ideas on how to fix it up.
各位，还要点什么吗？
Gentlemen, can I get you anything else?
再来一杯跟辛先生一样的，双份
Let's get another for Mr.Zimm. A double.
你就平白无故给我50万？
You're just going to give me 500 grand?
细节我们再谈，哈利 首先我想知道
We'll talk about that, but first I gotta know...
你怎么拉到智利帕玛这条线的？
how'd you hook up with Chili Palmer?
“勒夫乔伊先生”很棒 我会通知巴蒂开个会
'Mr.Lovejoy' was good. I'll call Buddy and set up a meeting.
- 好，巴蒂是谁？ - 他的经纪人
- Who's Buddy? - Lufkin, his agent.
- 凯伦认识他 - 你有兴趣吗？
- Karen knows him. - But you are interested?
何止有兴趣
I'm intrigued. You know what might help?
再看一次“终极风暴” 或许能帮助你
Another look at 'The Cyclone.'
了解怎么维系那种视觉质感
The way a visual fabric is maintained...
同时提升隐喻的层次
while the metaphor plays on different levels.
智利，那是你的车吗？
Hey, Chili, is this your ride?
是的，我喜欢坐高点，视野好
I like to sit up high. Check everything out.
它是凯迪拉克迷你休旅车
It is the Cadillac of minivans.
你看
Check this out.
可以借我开开看吗？
Mind if I take it for a spin?
他看雷特曼的谈话节目吗？ 那个智利帕玛鬼鬼祟祟的
He was watching Letterman? Sneaky, that Chili Palmer.
他找到那个身怀巨款的 干洗店老板了吗？
Did he find the dry cleaner, the one with all that money?
里欧？我不知道
Leo? I don't know.
我打赌他找到了
I bet he did,
但他一毛钱都不会给你 帮你解困…
but he ain't giving one penny of it to help you out.
不像我这么好心
Not the way I am.
假设我接受你的提议 什么时候可以拿到那50万？
Assuming I go along with this, when could I have the 500 grand?
随时
Whenever you want.
钱都是百元钞，用运动背包装里 放在机场保管箱
The money's in a jock bag in $100 bills out at the airport...
等着你去拿
just waiting in a locker to be picked up.
在机场？
At the airport?
因为一次未完成的买卖搁在那里
It was waiting on a deal that didn't go through.
详情你不必知道
You don't want to know.
我不知道我…
I don't know...
你不习惯做这种事
It's not the kind of thing you do, so I'm thinking.
我觉得你可以派智利帕玛去拿
Why not send your boy, Chili Palmer?
万一他被逮或中枪，你毫无损失
If he gets busted, hit on the head, you aren't out a thing.
C- 18
C-18.
神奇数字
Magic number.
我觉得不妥
我有把握 那是苏珊海沃
I'm positive. It was Susan Hayward.
不，是丽塔海沃丝和葛伦福特
No, it was Rita Hayworth and Glenn Ford.
抱歉，哈利
Excuse me, Harry.
在这里等我
Wait here.
为你介绍，他是我同事贝尔…
I'd like you to meet my associate, Bear.
特技演员，举重冠军 你可能早已知道
Movie stuntman, champion weight lifter, as you may have noticed.
专门为我扫除障碍
Throws things out I don't want.
我认为你应该乖乖回迈阿密去
You ought to turn around and go back to Miami.
- 你是特技演员？ - 对
You're a stuntman?
- 厉害吗？ - 我厉害吗？
- Any good? - Am I good?
以这种块头算不错了
That's not bad for a guy his size.
我给你一个机会
I'll make you a deal.
在我脱外套之前 如果你来得及逃走
If you can get out of here before I take my coat off...
我就不用拿你来擦地板 弄脏你昂贵的行头
I won't clean up the floor with you and mess up your pretty costume.
你不了解我
You don't know me.
你以为我怕你
You only think you do.
那家伙是特技演员
That guy is a stuntman.
他演过“怪谭2”
Yeah, he was in 'Creatures II.'
搞电影还真辛苦
Rough business this movie business.
我应该回去放高利贷 休息一阵子
I may have to go back to loan-sharking to take a rest.
哈利，你还跟这些家伙混什么？
What're you still doing with those guys?
他愿意无条件借我50万
He happens to be loaning me $500,000. No strings.
合约由我全权作主
I can write any kind of agreement I want.
- 现金还是支票？ - 现金
- Cash or check? - Cash.
现在已经放在 机场的保管箱里
It happens to be sitting at the airport in a locker at this moment.
机场保管箱？ 你应该不会这么笨吧
A locker at the airport. Jesus Christ, tell me you're not really that stupid.
你被设计了
You're being set up.
你不让他投资“怪谭” 他是在报复你
You cancelled that 'Freaks' deal. He's paying you back.
是吗？他设计我？
Is that right? He's setting me up?
为什么凯勒特叫我 派你去机场拿钱？
Why did Catlett say I should send you to the airport to pick it up?
因为你没有为我办一件屁事
You haven't done a thing for me since you got involved...
除了把我的剧本拿给波凯勒特看
except show Bo Catlett my script.
没错，哈利 被设计的人不是你
You're right. You're not the one being set up.
至少波投资过我三部电影
At least Bo has invested in three of my movies.
哈利，我们跟马丁谈过了
We spoke with Martin.
我们？
We?
- 阿智和我 - 真的？
- Chili and me. - Really?
他叫我们找巴蒂安排开个会
He asked us to call Buddy, set up a meeting.
开会… 你和凯伦？
A meeting. You and Karen?
这家伙才来两天
Guy's been in town two days...
他以为他是大制片大卫赛兹尼克
and already he thinks he's David O. fucking Selznick.
大制片，我应该跟波谈交易
Okay, Mr. O. Selznick, should I make my deal with Bo...
还是你愿意帮我找出 那个干洗店老板说服他投资？
or are you going to talk to your dry cleaner, if you find him?
我找到他了，但别指望里欧的钱
I found him, but forget about Leo's money.
你拿到钱了？
Do you have it?
如果里欧的钱给你 雷朋斯会追得你无处躲
If I gave you Leo's money, you'd have Ray Bones all over your ass.
- 那又是另一种麻烦 - 谁？
- That's a new kind of trouble. - Who?
雷巴波尼，住在迈阿密 老莫死后里欧的债务现在归他
Ray Barboni. He lives in Miami. He owns Leo now that Momo's dead.
老莫又是什么东西？老天！ 哪里冒出这堆名字？
Who the fuck is Momo? Where do you get these names?
我跟你说我可以怎么帮你
I tell you what I'll do for you.
明天趁人多的时候，我会去机场
I'll go to the airport tomorrow morning when it's crowded.
看看状况，如果没问题 我会帮你把钱拿回来
I'll check it out. If there's no problem, I'll get the money.
别抱太大希望
But don't get your hopes up.
或许我该打电话给这个雷巴波尼
Maybe I should call this Ray Barboni character...
问他愿不愿意投资我的电影
and see if he wants to invest in my movie?
别浪费时间，他不是电影迷
Don't waste your time. He's not a movie fan.
钥匙给我
Give me the key.
跟他说早上5点必须离开
Tell him he's gotta be out there by 5:00 in the morning.
因为演员只能工作一个晚上
Because the actor will only work one night, that's why.
我得挂了，对
I gotta go.
来了
Coming!
- 谁？ - 我
- Who is it? - Me.
噢，干！
Oh, fuck.
我听到了
I heard that.
哈罗，陶莉丝
Hello, Doris.
看起来你需要一个湿吻
Harry Zimm. You look like a wet kiss.
你喝的东西可以也让我尝尝吗？
Aren't you going to offer me whatever it is you taste like?
请进，陶莉丝
Come in, Doris.
我最喜欢的颜色…
My favorite color...
油灰色
putty.
我喜欢
I like it.
你想干嘛，陶莉丝？
What do you want?
（原子木乃伊）
（异形怪物）
- 我想念墨瑞，哈利 - 我也想念他
I miss Murray.Yeah, I miss him too.
他是非常棒的作家
A hell of a good writer.
我应该知道，是我发掘他的 让他有今天的成就
I should know. I discovered him, made him what he was.
不过是靠卖文字过日子
What he was was a hack.
除了帮你写剧本找不到别的工作
He couldn't get a job writing for anyone but you.
我说的是实话
I'm being honest.
他是烂作家，但是是个好丈夫
He was a lousy writer but a good husband.
可是当时我不明白
I just didn't know until it was too late.
人往往身在福中不知福 大家不都这么说吗
20/20 hindsight and all that. You know what they say.
我不喜欢孤独
I hate being alone.
我家好安静…
The house is so quiet.
好寂寞
So lonely.
我需要…
It needs...
男人的抚摸
a man's touch.
项链好漂亮，陶莉丝
Nice necklace, Doris.
我不知道该怎么说
I don't know how I feel about this.
你似乎没什么罪恶感
You seem to feel fine about it.
我是说道德上 你知道，墨瑞是我的朋友
I mean morally. You know, Murray was a friend.
墨瑞死了
Murray's dead.
意思是说
Does this mean that...
你会重新考虑 “勒夫乔伊先生”的条件？
you'll reconsider our deal on 'Mr.Lovejoy'?
不，但既然你提起了
No, but now that you mention it...
我跟派拉蒙一位年轻帅气 的主管谈过
I did talk to a gorgeous young executive at Paramount...
他刚好有机会接触这个剧本
who just happened to get his hands on the script.
- 他怎么说？ - 他说如果马丁有兴趣
What'd he say?
我可以轻松卖得50万
If Martin's interested, I can get half a million for it, easy.
别担心，哈利
Don't worry, Harry.
我会等你到星期五
I'm still giving you until Friday.
你好恐怖
How honorable of you.
你要我走？
You want me to go?
直接说，没关系
Just say so.
不管了
What the hell.
干！干！
Fuck, fuck, fuck.
- 干嘛？ - 雷巴波尼？
What? Ray Barboni?
你是谁？
Who is this?
你就是大家说的雷朋斯？
Is this the guy they call Ray Bones?
那得看你是谁？
It depends. Who is this?
我是谁？
Who is this?
我就是你最好乖乖听话的人
This is the one telling you the way it is.
好吧，猪头 想不想要你的30万？
Okay, asshole? You want your 300 grand, or don't you?
你说的是什么30万？
What 300 grand are you talking about?
一个叫里欧迪佛的家伙 从航空公司骗来的30万
The 300 grand a guy named Leo Devoe scammed off an airline.
现在落到智利帕玛手中的30万
The 300 grand Chili Palmer now has in his possession.
哈罗？你还在吗？
Hello? Are you there?
在，我在听 我不喜欢这样没名没姓的
I'm here. I just don't like this anonymous crap.
你要不是个胆小鬼 就是满口胡说八道
Either you're a big chickenshit, or you're not for real.
相信我，我说的是真的
Trust me. I am very for real.
好啊，那你是谁？
Then who are you?
- 我帮哈利辛工作 - 谁？
I happen to work for Harry Zimm, okay?
那个人是好莱坞的大人物
Who? Harry Zimm. The man happens to be a major Hollywood player.
我没听过
Never heard of him.
那是因为你从来不曾 踏出迈阿密一步，废人
Maybe because you've never been out of fucking Miami, dipshit.
或许你应该飞洛杉矶一趟 跟辛先生谈谈
Maybe you should get on a plane, come to LA, take a meeting with Mr.Zimm.
这位辛先生想怎么样 拾金不昧的酬金？
So this Zimm guy, is he asking for a finder's fee?
你是这个意思吗？
Is that what we're talking about?
辛先生什么都不要
Zimm don't ask for dick.
辛先生要你乖乖听话，不然
Zimm tells you the way it is, or else.
不然怎么样？
Or else what?
发挥你自己的想像力！
Or else use your fucking imagination!
（入境）
（劳德代尔堡 纽亚克 迈阿密 纽约）
（SV#83 纽亚克）
(C 18)
（威尔的故事）
抱歉，能不能请你帮个忙 我想给我太太一个意外惊喜
Excuse me. Can you help me out? I have a gift in here for my wife.
想请你把这东西 放到C- 17保管箱里
It's a surprise, and I was wondering if you could put this in locker C-17.
我给你10元，只要花2分钟
Ten bucks. Take you two minutes.
好吧
Yeah, okay.
（我爱洛杉矶）
这个给你
You'll need some of this.
快一点，她去上洗手间
Make it quick. She's in the john.
C- 17
C-17.
(C 18)
(C 17)
做得好
Good man.
（日本旅游团）
我们上，兄弟
Let's go, boys.
抱歉，先生
Excuse me, sir.
缉毒组干员寇蒂斯
Agent Curtis, Drug Enforcement.
他们是邓霸和摩根 请跟我们来
These are Agents Dunbar and Morgan. Would you come with us, please?
怎么回事？
What's going on?
跟他走，不要乱来
Let's follow him and behave ourselves.
（巴朋先生）
巴朋先生？欢迎光临洛杉矶 我叫巴比，你的司机
Mr.Barbone? Welcome to LA. I'm Bobby, your driver.
飞行还舒适吗？
Did you have a good flight?
很舒适，希望你开车的功夫 比碎碎念厉害，白痴
Yeah, but I hope you drive better than you fucking spell, jack-off.
我叫巴波尼，不是巴朋好吗？
The name is Barboni not Barbone, okay?
要先去饭店吗，爱斯科霸先生？
Want to go to the hotel first, Mr.Escobar?
我要去拿钱
I want to get my fucking money.
- 你住迈阿密？ - 对
- You live in Miami? - That's right.
来洛杉矶做什么？
Why are you in Los Angeles?
- 我是做电影的 - 投资者？
- I'm in movies. - You're an investor?
- 不，我是制片 - 有名片吗？
- No, I'm a producer. - Got a card in this?
还没印，刚开始 请问这是怎么回事
Not yet, I just got started. I'd like to know what this is all about.
我有法院授权对你脱衣搜身
I got a search warrant says I can strip-search you.
搜他身
Pat him down.
手贴在墙上
Put your hands on the wall.
- 腿张开 - 你在机场做什么？
Spread your legs. What are you doing at the airport?
我去接我太太 但她没坐那班飞机
Picking up my wife, but she wasn't on the plane.
你住迈阿密 太太怎么从纽亚克来？
If you live in Miami, why is your wife coming from Newark?
我们吵了一架，她回去布鲁克林
We had a fight. She left me. Went back to Brooklyn.
我打电话跟她说“到西部来
I called her and said, 'Why don't you come out west?
或许换个环境 我们可以破镜重圆”
Maybe a change of scenery will get us back together.
她说好，但显然又改变主意了
She said okay, but evidently she changed her mind.
- 你太太是湖人队球迷？ - 我是
- Wife a Lakers fan? - I am.
洛杉矶所有东西都令我着迷 我喜欢这里
I'm a fan of everything that's LA. I love it out here.
他没问题
He's clean.
- 你可以走了 - 你们到底在找什么？
You can go. What are you looking for?
炸弹还是什么？什么事？
A bomb?
一件不应该在那里的东西
Something that shouldn't be here.
是吗？
Is that right?
为什么不找人打开保管箱？ 或许可以找到
Get an attendant to open the lockers. Maybe you'll find it.
这主意不错，我们会考虑
I'll think about it.
我会那样做
I'd do that.
下次就不会抓错人
Then I'd get the right guy next time.
如果你想去海边 可以走这条公路
You ever want to go to the beach, here's the freeway you take.
周末不塞车
Of course, on the weekend there's no traffic.
我从海滩王国迈阿密来的 你叫我去看海？
I'm from Miami fucking Beach, and you want to show me the ocean?
那看太阳怎么样？
Does the sun ever shine in this town,
市区难道没太阳吗 还是都被烟雾遮住了？
or is this smog always around?
他们说都是因为烟雾弥漫 所以落日特别漂亮
They say the smog's the reason we have such beautiful sunsets.
他们是这么的说的吗？
That's what they say?
什么狗屁不通的道理
What a bunch of fucking bullshit.
我怎么可能忘记你这件衬衫
I don't know how I could have missed you in that shirt.
除了花色之外 跟上次那件都一样
The same as the other one except a different colored hibiscus, right?
你没带钥匙？
You didn't have the key on you?
不然我会站在这里？
You think I'd be standing here?
如果你想设计人并且奏效
If you're gonna set someone up, and you want it to work...
必须出人意料之外，记得吗？
it's gotta be a surprise.
看到他们了吗？
Spotted them?
你应该有演过那种 设计成功的电影
Did it work in some movie that you got beat up in?
我要跟你要回钥匙
Got to ask you for that key back.
等一下 设计我不成还要跟要回钥匙？
Wait. The setup didn't work, and you want the key back?
波说如果你没打开保管箱 上次的约定就取消
Bo said if you didn't open the locker, the deal's off.
开玩笑？
You're serious?
这就是你们做生意的方式？ 我很意外你能活到现在
This is how you guys do business? I'm surprised you're not dead.
钥匙我不可能还给你
There's no fucking way you'll get the key.
除非你用枪指着我 或许还有得谈
Unless you put a gun to my head. Then maybe we'll talk.
离开车子
Move away from the fucking car.
我不需要枪
I don't need a gun for you.
好啊 慢慢来
All right. Slow down.
用嘴巴呼吸
Breathe through your mouth.
慢，呼吸
Breathe.
贝尔，看着我
Bear, look at me.
跟你老板说，我不想再看到他
Tell your boss I don't wanna see him again.
他跟哈利谈妥了交易 交易就是交易
He made a deal with Harry, and a deal's a deal.
懂我意思吗？ 好啦，起来
Got that? Okay, get up.
你为什么跟那种人混在一起？
Why are you hanging around a guy like that?
你演过电影 你是特技演员，不是吗？
You were in the movies. You were stuntman, right?
他有过什么丰功伟业？
What's he ever done he can talk about?
- 你还好吧？ - 还好
- You okay? - Not too bad.
上次摔下楼梯没怎么样吧？
How about when you fell down the stairs?
大腿肌肉拉伤
Pulled my quadriceps.
你演过几部电影？
How many movies you been in?
大概60部
About 60.
不是盖的？
- No shit? - No shit.
说几部来听听？
What were some of them?
你都没看过啦
You didn't see none of them.
- 随便说几部嘛？ - 你没听过啦
哈利
Harry Zimm?
谁？
Who is it?
我就是那个不曾踏出 迈阿密一步的白痴
I'm the dipshit who's never been out of Miami.
巴波尼先生，稀客，稀客 很高兴你来访
Mr.Barboni, what a nice surprise. Good to see you.
请坐
Have a seat.
坐这，坐这
Right here.
巴波尼
Ray Bones.
巴波尼,对不起
Barboni, sorry.
他们说都是因为那些妈的烟雾
They say the fucking smog is the fucking reason...
所以这边的落日特别美
you have such beautiful fucking sunsets.
什么意思，他骗过他们了？
What do you mean he faked them out?
他知道是陷阱，所以有备而去
He knew it was a setup, and he was ready for it.
- 钱呢？ - 我想应该还在保管箱里
Where's the money? I guess it's still in the locker.
你想，意思是你不知道？
You guess? You mean you don't know?
不关我的事
I mean I don't care.
波，我不在乎
I really don't care.
贝尔，我待会打给你
I'll call you later.
爱斯科霸先生 什么风把你吹来洛杉矶的
Mr.Escobar, what a surprise. Welcome to LA.
- 我外甥呢？ - 你的谁？
- Where's my nephew? - You're who?
亚佑！他人呢？
Yayo! Where is he?
我没看到亚佑
I haven't seen Yayo.
他是我姊姊的儿子 没爸爸，脑袋有点不灵光
He's my sister's kid. No father. Not too bright.
我觉得他是个智障
I think he's a retard.
我是看我老姊面子 才给他那个任务
I only gave him the job as a favor to my sister. You understand.
家族纠葛，我了解
Family. I know how that goes.
他带我们的产品来到这里
He comes up here with our product.
他应该带50万回家才对 但一直没看到人影
He's supposed to return with $500,000. He never shows up.
我老姊快急疯了 她很担心，一直打电话给我
Meanwhile, my sister's going crazy. She calls all the time. She's worried.
我只关心我的钱到哪去了
Me? I just want to know what happened to my fucking money.
不知道，我把钱交给他了 然后送他离开
I gave the man his money and sent him on his way.
钱你给他了？
You gave him the money?
我给他放钱的保管箱的钥匙
I gave him a key to a locker that had the money in it.
你为什么把钱放在保管箱？
Why would you put the money in a locker?
因为航站大厦里有几亿个 缉毒组的干员
There were a zillion DEA guys hanging around the terminal.
几亿？
A zillion?
还真不少呢
That's a lot.
爱斯科霸先生 说不定你外甥一害怕逃跑了
Mr.Escobar, maybe your nephew panicked and took off.
你跟我说这些废话干嘛？
Why're you talking to me this bullshit?
我叫拉蒙和西萨用钉书机 把你的舌头钉在下巴上！
I think I have Ramon and Cesar staple your tongue to your chin!
你觉得怎么样？
What do you think?
我觉得你英语说得很好
I think you speak very good English, Mr.Escobar.
我们周末住在环球喜来登饭店
We're spending the weekend at the Universal Sheraton.
去观光一下，看看鲨鱼
Take the tour. See the shark.
参观“迈阿密风云”拍摄现场
Check out that 'Miami Vice' action spectacular.
嗯，很棒
Nice.
然后我们会回来
After, we're going to come back here...
拿我的钱
get my money.
是的
Oh yeah
还有亚佑
And Yayo too.
他的混帐外甥？
His fucking nephew?
到市区的话到银行去 从礼车公司户头多领些钱出来
Go to the bank. Raid the limo account.
我现在在市区，但有屁用 银行根本没有钱
We got dick in the bank.
全部拿去投资哈利的电影了
We dumped it all into Harry's movie.
我说的是你，雷巴波尼
I'm talking about you, Ray Barboni...
在大制作电影里占一些股份
owning a piece of a major motion picture.
至于占多少由你自己决定
How much of a piece is entirely up to you.
我是说你可以投资 帕玛欠你的30万里…
I'm saying you could invest part of the 300 grand...
的一部份或全部
that Palmer owes you or all of it.
完全由你自己决定
It's up to you.
智利帕玛呢？里欧迪佛呢？
Where's Chili Palmer? Where's Leo Devoe?
我的钱呢？
Where's my fucking money?
雷…看着我
Ray, look at me.
- 什么？ - 看着我，雷
What? Look at me.
你说，看着你？
Did you say look at you?
看着我，雷
Look at me, Ray.
我跟你说，哈利
I'll tell you what, Harry.
你他妈给我看这个
Take a fucking look at this.
再看看这个
And have a peek at this.
知道吗，哈利，这个…
You know, Harry, this...
才是我需要的…
is the exact fucking thing I needed.
稍微运动一下…
A little fucking exercise...
因为飞机实在…
after that long... fucking...
实在坐太久了
plane ride.
你麻烦大了，哈利
You got a big problem, Harry.
噢，哈利，别昏倒
Come on, Harry, don't pass out on me.
看着我，哈利
Look at me, Harry.
我的钱呢？
Where's my money? Where's my money?
哈利，我再问你一次
I'll ask you one more time...
然后，再不说回答重点 我会让你一枪毙命
then I gotta shoot you, you don't tell me what I want.
我的钱呢？
Where's my money?
你的钱？
Your money?
你他妈是谁？
Who the fuck are you?
迈阿密来的雷巴波尼
I'm Ray Barboni, from Miami.
我怎么听不懂这有什么意义？
Like that's supposed to mean something?
你脚下那个人是我们的
The man you're standing on belongs to me and my partner, bro'.
- 这人渣欠我钱 - 排队
- This piece of shit owes me money. - Get in line.
但我不喜欢排队
I don't like waiting in line.
老大，这里不是迈阿密 要什么东西先来问我
Tough shit. This ain't Miami. You want something, you talk to me.
去你的，去死吧
No, no, fuck you, fuckball.
洛杉矶是个开放的城市 我做什么不需要得到别人的批准
LA is an open city, and I don't think I have to get permission... from nobody for nothing.
是吗？
Really?
这城市刚刚被我包下了
I just closed it.
看你的枪深深的插在腰带里
You must be one of those quick-draw artists...
你一定是俗称的快枪侠
because you got your gun stuck way down in your belt.
那是什么枪？ 义大利制的．9手枪？
What do you got there? A wop nine?
跟飞雅特同级的烂货 重要时机老是卡住
Fucking Fiat of guns, always jamming at the wrong time.
不要吐到我的鞋子，哈利
Don't you puke on my shoes, Harry.
我想请你帮个忙
I want you to do me a favor.
把这枪拿去
I want you to take this gun...
赏那位老兄一颗子弹
and put a pill in the bro' over there.
我知道你在想什么 “他已经死了，干嘛还射他？”
I know you're thinking, 'Why fucking shoot him? He's already dead.'
警方可以检验得出来
But you see, the police have these tests...
你是否开过枪
tell you whether or not a guy fired a gun...
我不曾来过这里
and I was never here.
你懂我意思吗，哈利？ 我没来过
Understand, Harry? I was never here.
如果你说有
If you say I was...
我会再回来 然后把你从那扇窗户扔出去
I'll come back and throw you out the fucking window.
别婆婆妈妈，我们时间不多
Knock it off, Harry. We haven't got a lot of time.
很好
That's it. That's it.
多逍遥自在
Not a worry in the world.
游泳池该捞落叶了
Your pool needs skimming.
马丁打来 方便的话，他明天想一起吃午饭
Martin wants to have lunch tomorrow, if you can make it.
- 看谁要出钱罗 - 当然不是马丁
Depends on who pays.
电影明星从来不买单 他们都吃米不知道米价
Definitely not Martin. Movie stars never pick up the check. They have no idea what things cost.
很多连自己的电话号码都不知道 更多不知道邮递区号
Most of them don't know their phone number or zip code.
我不晓得 很难接受你们曾经在一起
I can't imagine the two of you together.
你不太喜欢他是吗？
You don't like Martin much, do you?
不，我喜欢他 我觉得他…
No, I do. I do. I think he's--
太矮了
I think he's short.
我知道他是个好演员 但你到底看上他哪一点？
I know he's a good actor, but what was it exactly that you saw in him?
马丁那时跟现在不一样
Martin was different then.
他那时候还不是电影明星
He wasn't a movie star.
你的故事怎么样了？
Anyway, what about your story?
想到片名了吗？
Thought of a title?
叫“黑道当家”怎么样？
How about, 'Get Shorty?'
叫“阿智好莱坞历险记” 怎么样？
How about, 'Chili's Hollywood Adventure?'
不知道，那是不一样的故事 我还在想那一部
That's a different story. I'm still working on that one.
我还在构思它的影像质感
I'm still getting the visual fabric together.
但我又加了点剧情
But I have added to it.
现在有女主角了
There's a girl in it now.
真的？
Really?
她跟你很像
She looks a lot like you.
我觉得你可以当演员
I think you could be an actor.
我知道你有时在演戏 但不愿意让人看出来
I know you're acting sometimes, but you don't show it.
你觉得我在作假？
You thought I was faking?
那时候没有
No, not then.
我是说通常
I mean in general.
你指的不是电影明星，对吧？ 你是说，演技派演员
You don't mean a movie star, right? You mean more like a character actor?
两者都是
Well, whichever.
我看到劳勃迪尼诺的角色里 有我的影子
I could see myself in the parts a Robert DeNiro plays.
艾尔帕西诺的狠角色 也跟我有点像
Maybe even an Al Pacino movie. I'm playing a real hard-on.
但我就是无法想像自己演 “三个奶爸一个娃”那种电影
I can't see myself in a movie where 3 guys get left with a baby...
他们根本不知道怎么照顾婴儿 所以耍白烂
and they act like 3 grown-up assholes, like they're all cute.
- 我没办法… - 阿智，看着我
Chili, look at me.
请留言
Leave a message.
凯伦，我是陶莉丝
Hi, Karen, it's Doris.
美人，今晚到西达医院来看哈利
You might want to come by Cedars tonight and visit Harry.
他在急诊室里
He's in the emergency room.
我们走
Let's go.
我能跟你们说什么？ 我去他办公室找他
I stopped by his office...
看他愿不愿意带我去吃法国料理
to see if he wanted to take me to Le Dome for dinner.
我看到哈利和另一个人躺在地上
I saw Harry and some other man lying on the floor.
晚安，陶德 晚安，路易士
Good night, Todd. Good night, Louis.
- 噢，天啊 - 哈利，我的天啊
- Jesus. - Harry, my God.
- 他不能说话 - 怎么回事？
He can't talk. He's full of Demerol. What happened?
根据陶德…蓝道警官…
According to Todd-- Sergeant Randall--
一个叫隆尼的人 到哈利的办公室去收欠款
a man named Ronnie came by Harry's office to collect on a debt.
他动粗，所以哈利对他开枪
He got rough, and Harry shot him.
你杀了隆尼？
You shot Ronnie?
哈罗，事情是这样的
Hello, hello. Okay, here we go.
辛先生下巴碎裂 脖子有外伤
Looks like Mr.Zimm has a broken jaw and some neck trauma...
手部骨折
to go with these fractured hands.
失陪，各位
Excuse us, folks.
哈利，明天马丁约我们 在长春藤吃午餐
Martin wanted to meet us for lunch tomorrow at the Ivy.
我可以取消，但他下周要去坎城
I'd cancel, but he's going to Cannes next week...
我认为阿智和我还是应该去
so I really think maybe Chili and I should still go.
谁要练习帮辛先生缝下巴
Who wants to take a crack at wiring Mr.Zimm's jaw?
（恐怖片制作人 疑涉入枪击案）
混蛋
Son of a bitch.
嗨，波
Hi, Bo!
嘿，法拉，小宝贝
Hey, Farrah.
- 进来前有擦脚吗？ - 有
Little honey bunny. You wipe your feet before you came in?
好乖
That's my girl.
波叔叔的地毯 就能保持干净洁白
Keep Uncle Bo's carpet nice and white.
我一直打电话找你，你去哪里？
I been calling you, man. Where you been?
- 看到报纸了吗？ - 看到了
See the paper?
我不相信
Yeah, I seen it. I don't believe it.
报上说哈利对隆尼开5枪…
Says Harry shot Ronnie five times.
四枪打穿胸腔，一枪打到脚
Four through the chest and one through his foot?
打到脚，天啊，可怜的隆尼
His foot, Jesus. Poor Ronnie.
今晚给你一个任务 轻松的任务
Tonight, I got one for you that doesn't involve any heavy work.
去智利帕玛的饭店房间看看
Go take a look around Chili's hotel room.
不，我没办法
I can't.
我要带法拉去哥斯达梅沙 找他妈妈
I gotta take Farrah over to her mother's in Costa Mesa...
反正无关紧要，我不干了！
and that don't matter, 'cause I quit.
我不想再为你工作了 我来跟你当面说清楚
I don't work for you no more. I came to tell you...
免得有什么误会
to your face, so we got no misunderstanding.
哥伦比亚人来洛杉矶 因为钱的事正在不爽
The Colombians are in LA, all upset about their money.
要死不死那个佑佑 刚好是爱斯科霸的外甥
If that ain't enough, it turns out that Yo-Yo was Escobar's nephew.
那是你的问题，人是你杀的
That's your problem. You shot the guy.
小可爱，来这里，法拉 过来，小宝贝
Honey bunny. Come here. Come here, honey bunny.
来看看波叔叔，快来，乖！
Come see Uncle Bo.
你知道波叔叔怕寂寞
You know Uncle Bo hates being alone.
他实在太怕寂寞了
In fact he hates it so much...
连跌倒时都想有人陪着
he takes a fall, he's not going to fall by himself.
他愿意当污点证人 再也顾不了他的特技替身
He'll plea-deal his way out.
他会被当成西岸第一大毒枭哦 只要他们愿意减轻他的刑责
Give up his ace stuntman, now one of the West's dope kings... if they go easy on the cat.
听说联邦监狱 父亲节的时候
I hear in federal joints they let you spend an extra five minutes...
会让囚犯多5分钟 跟女儿会面
with your daddy on Father's Day.
放开她，波
Let her go.
办完这件事，我就辞职 可以吧？
After this one, I'm out. You understand?
这是我们最后一次交谈
This is the last time we talk to each other.
你记得哈利的故事吧 帕玛在找的那个干洗店老板
Remember Harry's story about the dry cleaner Palmer was after--
A了航空公司30万那家伙？
the one who stole $300,000 from the airline?
记得，他怎么了？
What about him?
今晚去看看帕玛的饭店房间 我去凯伦的家瞧瞧
Tonight, look around Palmer's hotel room while I check out Karen's place.
说不定他没藏在别的地方 午夜回来这里跟我碰面
See if he hasn't stashed it somewhere. Meet me back here at midnight.
这家长春藤是什么菜？
What kind of food do they got at this Ivy place?
欧陆式，但无所谓 马丁不看菜单点餐
Continental, but it doesn't matter. Martin won't order from the menu.
为什么？
Why not?
电影明星从来不按菜单点餐
Movie stars can never order straight from the menu.
他们非想出一些菜单上 没有的菜不可
They have to think of something they have to have that isn't on the menu.
哈利，你怎么来了？ 你应该待在医院
Why're you here? You're supposed to be in the hospital.
你这个样子很适合演你的恐怖片
You look like you should be in one of your horror movies.
我的案子
My project!
- 他说什么？ - “我的案子”
- What did he say? - My project.
辛先生！
Mr.Zimm.
哈利！干得好，杀手
Thattaboy, Killer!
这边请
Right this way.
你是名人，哈利 你早就开枪杀人了
You're a celebrity. Should've shot someone a long time ago.
嗨
Hi
抱歉，你好 哈罗
Excuse me. How're you?
你好吗？嘿，阿智 很高兴又见面了
- Good to see you. - Great to see you.
我的天啊，噢！
Oh, my goodness.
- 嗨，马丁 - 漂亮宝贝
Sweet face.
- 真漂亮，而且很香 - 谢谢
You look great. Smell good too.
哈利，听说你经历了一场浩劫
I hear you had quite an experience.
幸好人还好
Anyway, I'm glad you're okay.
还有件事你知道吗？ 很高兴10年前你拒绝了我
You know what else? I'm really glad you rejected me ten years ago...
那时我去参加 你的电影“生日男孩”
when I auditioned for Eddie Solomon,
那个恋童癖角色 艾迪所罗门的试镜
the pedophile clown in 'Birthday Boy.'
如果接了那个角色 说不定我今天就被定型了
If I'd have gotten that part, I might have been typecast.
点菜了吗？点完我要点别的
Have you guys ordered? I have something after this.
可以点菜吗？抱歉，麻烦…
Can we order? Excuse me, can you--
- 你叫什么名字？ - 史黛芬妮
- Hi, what's your name? - Stephanie.
嗨，史黛芬妮
- Stephanie.
我要一份蛋卷 可以麻烦只用蛋白
Can you make me an egg white omelette but with shallots?
加青葱，微焦 一点点橄榄油，不加盐？
Shallots only slightly browned, very little olive oil. And no salt.
- 装一盘，我们分着吃 - 不
Why don't you bring one for the table? We'll all pick on it.
我知道，冰草莓汁怎么样…
I know, how about having those strawberry frappes?
里面有小草莓那种饮料？ 给哈利两根吸管
The drink with the little strawberries. Bring two straws for Harry.
故事的浪漫观点非常重要
I think the romance angle in your story is critically important.
绝对不能是那种稀松平常的邂逅
It shouldn't be just a hop in the sack for either of them.
他们两个应该深爱着对方
They should fall deeply in love.
哪两个？
Which two?
等到他们面临危险
Later, when their lives are in danger...
黑道份子开始追杀他们时 能够提高故事的张力
and the mob guy is chasing them, it not only heightens the tension...
而且为他们的恋情增加点愁绪
but it adds a wistful element to their romance.
- 黑道份子？ - 我得考虑一下，演黑道份子
Mob guy? I have to consider, as the mob guy...
又睡了别人的老婆，所以…
it's another man's wife I'm sleeping with.
毕竟你们很有道德感
And you have such morals.
黑道份子？
Mob guy?
我得走了 我很想看到的是…
I have to run. What I'd like to see is that...
他们开始因为觊觎那些钱而不安
they begin to have misgivings about wanting the money.
这是他们道德上的两难
This becomes a moral dilemma.
他们想说服自己收下来 但最后还是没办法接受
They rationalize taking it, but in the end, they can't.
什么钱？
What money?
那30万啊，不然还有什么钱？
The 300 large. What other money is there?
我应该先看剧本再来谈
I know I shouldn't talk about it until I've read the script...
但我已经有强烈的感觉
but I have such a good feeling about this.
我是放高利贷的
I am that shylock.
看着我，哈利！
Look at me.
不错，掌握到神髓了
Not bad. You're getting it down.
太了解他，我自己都害怕了
It scares me how well I know this guy.
我明天就能演，不需要再准备了
I could do this tomorrow, no further preparation.
漂亮宝贝…
Dollface.
你应该考虑回来演戏
You really should think about getting back into acting.
- 我们可以演点对手戏 - 我会慎重考虑
We could do something together.
好的
I'll give it some heavy thought.
多保重，哈利
Take care of yourself.
请用
Enjoy.
我来帮你，来
Here, let me help you out. Go ahead.
用力吸
Suck harder.
阿智，起来，楼下有人
Wake up! Somebody's downstairs.
是哈利
It's Harry.
你怎么知道？
How do you know?
学你的方式报复你… 在看雷特曼的深夜谈话节目
He's doing the same thing you did. Playing 'Letterman' on TV.
不是谈话节目，是电影
That's not Dave. That's a movie.
- 你下不下去？ - 不知道
- You going down? - I don't know.
不知道？
You don't know?
我去
I don't know. I'm going.
- 凯伦，你有枪吗？ - 没有
- Karen, you got a gun? - No!
- 任何枪都可以 - 没有
- Any kind of gun will do. - No!
好像是“赤胆屠龙”
Sounds like 'Rio Bravo.'
这个可能有帮助
May be this will help
我想我要喝那杯酒，查理
Guess I'll take that drink now, Charlie.
我知道你会喝
I thought you would.
想要那把枪吗？捡起来啊
You want that gun? Pick it up.
希望你去捡
I wish you would.
我要钱
I need the money.
什么钱？
What money?
你从做干洗的 里欧那拿来的30万
The 300 grand you got from a dry cleaner named Leo.
我把话说清楚
Let's me get this straight.
你非法侵入凯伦的家
You break into Karen Flores' house...
来索取不属于你的30万
and you ask for 300 grand that doesn't belong to you.
钱给我，我马上走
Give me the money.
我不敢相信你们这里 做生意的规矩
I can't believe how you guys do business out here.
你们的组织真的是烂得吓人
I can't believe how fucked up your organization is.
我数到3
How about I count to three
你把你的脑浆好好组织到墙壁上 怎么样？1…
and organize your brain all over the wall? One.
你要对我开枪，波？
You're going to shoot me?
- 稍等一下，2… - 我不相信
- Just a second. Two. - I can't believe this.
她现在不能说话
She can't talk right now.
叫得真好听 他们应该让你多演几部
That's a nice scream. They ought to give you more work.
钱可以给你，但不在这里
All right, I'll get you the money, but it's not here.
- 我可以去拿 - 没问题
- I gotta go get it. - Okay, fine.
她先跟着我，以策安全
In the meantime, I'll hold her for safekeeping.
- 你知道月桂谷吗？ - 我找得到
- Do you know Laurel Canyon? - I'll find it.
我在奇地大道8150号 一出月桂谷就到了
8150 Wonderland Avenue. Right off Laurel.
我一定会去，凯伦
I'll be there, Karen.
- 钱拿到了？ - 没有
- You get the money? - No.
- 这是怎么回事？ - “B”计划
- What is this? - Plan B.
不必拘束
Make yourself comfortable.
- 凯伦是“B”计划？ - 不要问，贝尔
- 她是电影明星！ - 我管她是什么人
- She's a movie star! - I don't care!
- 我的天啊 - 做点交易 - 交易什么？ - 钱？
For chrissake. - Going to make a trade. - For what?
绑架会被判终生监禁！
- The money. - You get life for kidnapping.
- 冷静点，贝尔 - 这可是终生监禁的大事
- Calm down. - Life in prison!
- 我怎么冷静得了？ - 不要临阵叛变，贝尔
- You want me to calm down! - Do not fade on me, Bear.
现在你想杀我？
What, are you going to shoot me now?
动手啊！一了百了反而痛快
Go ahead! Put me out of my misery!
我叫你他妈冷静点
Calm the hell down...
除非你想一辈子坐牢
unless you want to spend the rest of your life holding Farrah...
在一堆重刑犯的牢里抱小法拉！
in a room full of goddamned felons!
这就是那些盖在悬崖边的房子
So! This is one of them houses you see hanging off the side of the cliff.
凯伦呢？
Where's Karen?
在我浴室里，钱呢？
In my bathroom. Where's the money?
- 我要先看到她 - 去看啊
- Let me see her. - Go ahead.
你还好吗？
You okay?
这家伙的马桶是粉红色的
Guy's got a fucking pink toilet!
她真正点，钱给我
She's great. Give me the money.
首先，我们之间的事先解决
First, I'm gonna settle something between you and me.
我以前中过枪…
Now, I've been shot at before...
一次是意外，两次是蓄意的 但我还活到现在
once by accident, twice on purpose...
只要我愿意我还可以活下去
and I'm still here. I'm gonna be here as long as I want.
这表示你得去别的地方…
Which means you gotta be somewhere else.
不要靠近我、凯伦和哈利
Nowhere near me, Karen or Harry.
钱给你
Here's your money.
电影的事就交给 学有专精的我们
Take it and leave... the movie business to the rest of us who know what we're doing.
我们走，凯伦
Come on, Karen.
你非法侵入我家，我有人证
You broke in my house, and I have a witness to it.
什么？ 这次不是“勇闯黄金城”
What?
约翰韦恩或迪恩马丁 对坏蛋开枪了
Only this time it ain't no John Wayne or Dean Martin shooting bad guys...
那部片是“赤胆屠龙”
- in 'El Dorado.' - That was 'Rio Bravo.'
“勇闯黄金城”的醉汉 是劳勃密勤
Robert Mitchum played the drunk in 'El Dorado.'
“赤胆屠龙”的醉汉是迪恩马丁
Dean Martin played the drunk in 'Rio Bravo.'
基本上是一样的角色 约翰韦恩两部都有演
Basically, it was the same part. John Wayne did the same in both.
他演约翰韦恩
He played John Wayne.
我巴不得马上给你死
Man, I can't wait for you to be dead.
你不让他跟我说…
Are you going to--
这是还你那次楼梯事件 这是还你机场的事！
That's for the stairs, and that's for the airport.
开始流血前，把他拖离我的地毯
Get him off my carpet before he starts to bleed.
这家伙要给他死吗？
You want to take this guy out?
出去阳台，弄成是他来找麻烦
Come out to the deck. Make it look like he came at us.
你开枪打他，自卫
You shoot him. Self-defense.
起来 他应该拿把刀或什么的
- Shouldn't he have a weapon? A knife?
待会再塞在他手里
- Get it later.
好了，贝尔，够了！
All right, that's enough.
再打下去 看起来就不像非法入侵了
You keep hitting him like that, he won't look like he broke in.
比较像先被毒打，然后中枪
It'll look like somebody beat him up and then shot him.
不，不会
No, he ain't.
等等，我们得离开这里
Hold on! We gotta get out of here!
你在干嘛？
What are you doing?
- 凯伦，你在干嘛？ - 噢，糟糕！
- What are you doing? - Oh, shit.
她在对我们开枪！
She's shooting at us!
对不起！
I'm sorry. I'm sorry.
怎么会这样？
How do you think that happened?
我怎么知道
Beats the shit out of me.
你害怕吗？
Were you scared up there?
不怕才怪
You bet.
- 看起来不像
You don't act like it.
现在不害怕了  你要我怕多久？
I was scared then, not now. How long you want me to be scared?
我马上回来
I'll be right back.
- 你怎么进来的？ - 简单
How'd you get in?
我跟他们说我是你 只要装得很笨，他们就相信我啦
It was easy. I told them I was you. I acted real stupid, and they believed me.
来洛杉矶干嘛，朋斯？
What brings you to LA, Bones?
不要污辱我，转过来
Please, don't insult me. Just turn around.
转过来
Turn around!
你是我这辈子见过最笨的人
Do you know that you're the dumbest fuck I've ever met?
口袋我检查一下
Let me look in these pockets.
里欧迪佛的事，你一找到他 就应该告诉我
You should've told me about Leo as soon as you found out.
- 我为什么要那样做？
Why would I do that?
- 因为他是我的客户  笨蛋，他是我的
Because he's a customer of mine. Dummy. He belongs to me.
好小子 这是什么？
Well, well, well. What have we here?
“C- 18”
C-18.
这是什么东西？
I wonder what this could be?
保管箱钥匙？
A locker key?
哪里的保管箱？
But where's the locker?
袋子我放在机场
I checked the bag at the airport.
哪个航站？
Which terminal? Which terminal!
君王
Sovereign.
你找到里欧了？
You found Leo.
你找到他，拿走那可怜虫的钱 放在保管箱里，随时准备落跑
You took the poor bastard's money. You put it in a locker ready to go.
- 你怎么还没走？ - 我喜欢这里
Why haven't you left? I like it out here.
阿智，我经常想…
You know, Chili, I've been thinking.
我们没道理相处不好
There's really no reason why you and I shouldn't get along.
以前发生的事把它忘了
Forget all the stuff that happened.
我不记得我们的冲突 是怎么开始的
I don't even remember how this mess started.
你随便找个理由就修理我 我说算了
You took a swing at me for some fucking thing. I say, 'Fuck it.'
你欠我钱，我也说算了
I say you owe me money. Fuck that.
我说你欠我利息钱 我也说算了
I say you owe me the juice on the money? Fuck that too.
我说，不管他死活
I say live and let die.
但这件事…
But this...
绝对是我们之间的秘密
is strictly between you and I.
你不准跟任何人提，懂吗？
You say nothing... to nobody about this. Understood?
- 你说了就算数，雷 - 这样很公平，你觉得呢？
Whatever you say. I think it's only fair.
我们的恩怨一笔勾消
Then it's all settled.
再见
I'll see you around.
笨猪
Dumb fuck.
过来
Come on.
去他妈的机场
The fucking airport.
上钩了，我们上
Bingo, boys. Let's go.
嘿，朋斯，看着我
Hey, Bones, look at me.
去你的，去你妈
Fuck you, fuckball.
干
Damn!
卡！卡！
Cut! Cut!
- 我没按错啊 - 你按错了
- I'm pushing the right button. - You're not, or it wouldn't fall.
不然东西不会掉下来
Every take I push the right button.
贝尔，教他怎么用好吗？
Bear, man, you show him how to do it.
我不知道，可能是…
I don't really know.
- 你想怎么办，哈利？ - 我们会想办法
What do you want to do, Harry?
收工，明天再来 干！
Wrap. It's a wrap. Come back tomorrow.
哈利，你好吗？ 你应该加班赶拍这个镜头
What're you doing? You should've gone into overtime to get that shot.
才开拍两天 进度已经落后两周了
This is only the second day. We're already two weeks behind.
帮个忙，好吗？
Do me a favor, okay?
这里我搞不懂 马丁跟我说过他很喜欢
I don't understand. Martin told me that he loves it.
巴蒂，我觉得马丁不对劲
I just don't think Martin is right, okay?
- 为什么不对劲？ - 因为他太矮了
- Why the hell not? - He's too short.
走
Come on.
为什么他非用马丁威尔不可？
Why does he keep pushing Martin?
整体考量
Packaging.
马丁威尔不可能变成梅尔吉勃逊
You can't make a Martin Weir into a Mel Gibson.
要去摩顿还是丹塔亚吃饭？
Where do you want to go? Morton's or Dan Tana's?
不知道
I don't know
（马丁威尔 潘尼马歇尔）
（智利帕玛）
（纪念丹尼吉尔）